（巴里艾伦）
祝您今天愉快
Have a brilliant day.
谢谢
Yeah, thank you.
你也是
You too.
早上好 想点些什么
Morning. What can I get you?
那位卷发女士呢
Where's curly-hair lady?
萨拉吗
Sara?
她生病了 反正她请假时是这么说的
She's out sick. Or at least, that's what she says.
其实是交新男友了
She's got a new boyfriend.
想点什么 跟我说就行
What can I get you?
我通常都点一样的
Usually it's my usual
我赶时间 她会提前备好
and she usually has it ready because I'm usually late.
那就快点儿告诉我吧
Well, don't keep me in suspense.
PB和BRHC组合三明治
Um, it's a PB and BRHC on a roll.
我记一下
Okay, so...
PB指的是花生酱 我没猜错吧 没错
-"PB" would be peanut butter, I'm assuming? -Yes.
BR是香蕉 葡萄干
"BR," bananas, raisins.
H是蜂蜜 C是奶酪
"H," honey. "C," cheese on a roll.
新陈代谢快的人真是有口福
Aren't you blessed with a fast metabolism.
你这是要去跑马拉松吗
Are you running a marathon or something?
说起来 我妹妹倒是跑过一次
You know, my sister ran a marathon once,
老天保佑她
God rest her soul.
人没事 就是累得半死不活
She's not dead. She's just exhausted.
不就是跑了个步吗 莎伦
We get it, Sharon. You ran.
但我们早上都要去上班啊
But everyone has to work in the morning.
是啊 我上班已经迟到三分钟了
Yeah, I have to go to work, three minutes ago.
不好意思 我想快点儿吃到我的三明治
And, sorry, I'm in sort of a rush for the sandwich.
老兄 心急可吃不到好三明治啊
You can't rush a good sandwich, dude.
（阿尔弗雷德）
阿尔弗雷德 等会儿说
Alfred, really can't talk.
早上好啊 艾伦先生
Good morning, Mr. Allen.
不好 我迟到了
No, I'm late.
而且快饿死了 卷发姑娘今天不在
And I'm starving, and curly-haired girl isn't here
她叫萨拉 有男朋友
and her name is Sara, and she has a boyfriend.
哥谭总医院这边出乱子了
We have a situation at Gotham General.
是由抢劫引发的
A robbery gone wrong.
现在可是大白天
This is the middle of the morning.
我们那位蝙蝠朋友不是应该在睡觉吗
Why is our bat-friend even awake?
叫超人去
Call Superman.
我先想到的他
That was my first thought.
可惜他正在忙别的事
Sadly, he's otherwise engaged.
这是一座位于中美洲的活火山
...active volcano in Central America.
（突发新闻 危地马拉一火山爆发）
又是这样
Classic.
戴安娜呢
What about Diana?
我也考虑过了
My other first thought.
可她不接电话 我能有什么办法
Rather annoyingly, she's not picking up.
原来是找不到其他人了
How many first thoughts, exactly,
才想起来找我的 是吧
did you have before you first thought of me?
跟她有什么关系
...never about her.
是关乎你自己的 抱歉 我的三明治好了吗
-This is about you. -Hi, sorry. Is my sandwich...
去年在船上时 我算是长教训了
I learned my lesson on the boat last year.
我的那个妹妹可真是酒后吐真言
Stuff my sister comes out with when she's drunk.
就连对我妈妈的朋友也是一通数落
Personal comments about my mom's friends as well,
她居然好意思说别人
which I think is what I say about her...
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
是闪电侠
Flash!
你好
Hi.
我爱你I love you.
谢谢
Thank you.
我觉得你人也很好
You seem very nice also.
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
让韦恩先生跟你说
Patching you into Mr. Wayne.
别 拜托
No, please don't.
抱歉 这么问你可能有点儿怪
Oh, my God. Sorry if this sounds weird,
那个巧克力棒 你还吃吗
but are you actively eating that candy bar?
能扔给我吗
Maybe you could throw it to me?
以正义的名义
In the name of justice.
好啊 好啊
Yes, yes.
我需要你抓紧过来 巴里
I need you here now, Barry.
嗨 布鲁斯
Hi, Bruce.
知道了 我
Yes, I'm...
来了
coming.
剧名：闪电侠
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并
（哥谭市）
糟了 各部门
No!
不 不
No, no!
布鲁斯 这里的情况简直糟透了
Bruce, this is a huge mess.
你人在哪儿呢
Why aren't you here?
布鲁斯 怎么听着像是你正在跑路啊
Bruce, why does it sound like you're fleeing the scene?
法尔科内的傻儿子想干票大的
Falcone's idiot kid decided to try to play in the big leagues.
召集了一伙人 闯进了哥谭总医院的实验室
He put a crew together and broke into the lab at Gotham General.
偷走了一种致命病毒
Stole a highly deadly virus.
被我拦截时 他们炸开了一条出路
I intercepted them, but they blasted their way out.
医院那边就靠你了 巴里
You can handle the hospital, Barry.
我这边还得忙着拯救世界
Somebody has to save the rest of the world, so I was gonna do that.
希望你不要介意
If you don't mind.
说得很在理 布鲁斯
Sounds about right, Bruce.
喂 小心
谢谢你从坑里救了我 闪电侠
"Thanks for saving me from the sinkhole, Flash."
巴里 煤气管道和水管破裂
Barry, gas and water pipes ruptured.
（警告 煤气管道破裂）
在地下室
In the basement.
知道了
Right.
这就去
On it.
你那边能打开吗
Can you open it?
好像卡住了
-I think it's locked. -It's jammed.
天啊 打不开啊
God, it's not working!
拜托
Oh, please!
我说 阿尔弗雷德 我已经认了
Look, Alfred. I've come to accept
我在正义联盟里就是个收拾烂摊子的角色
that I'm essentially the janitor of the Justice League.
差事虽然苦
Which sucks.
但是我也认了
But I've come to accept it.
可是
But...
我怎么觉得
I can't help but notice...
每次这个烂摊子的罪魁祸首
that it always seems to be a bat-mess...
都是蝙蝠侠
that I'm cleaning up.
（停车）
当心
Look out!
小心
如果我的推算是正确的
If my calculations are correct,
从以往的经验来看 通常是正确的
and history will prove they usually are,
那么地基的损毁
the foundational damage is
将会导致整个东翼建筑的坍塌
about to cause the collapse of the east wing.
东翼没事啊
East wing's fine.
有我在
All right, I got you.
幸好没事 我速度要跟不上了
Which is good because my speed is lagging.
（热量过低）
我还饿着肚子呢 阿尔弗雷德
Running on empty, Alfred.
听见没
Do you hear that?
是我的肚子在叫
That's my stomach.
不 不
No, no.
是东翼坍塌的声音
It's the collapsing east wing.
巴里 30楼
Barry, 30th floor.
在下
There's a
宝宝
baby...
雨
Shower.
（能量达到峰值）
艾伦先生
Mr. Allen,
我太为你感到骄傲了
you've made me very proud.
妈妈们会很感激你的
And a lot of mothers very happy.
好了
Okay.
我知道
I understand
刚才发生的这一切可能会给你带来心理创伤
that these events can be psychologically scarring.
到时候你可以找心理咨询师寻求帮助
You should seek the services of a mental health professional.
在这方面 正义联盟暂时做得还不够好
The Justice League is not very good at that part yet.
相信我
Trust me.
天啊
God.
快甩掉他
Shake him off!
要是让那个公文包掉进水里
If that briefcase falls into the water,
（病毒传播模拟）
午饭前就可能有一半的哥谭市民丧命
it could wipe out half of Gotham by lunchtime.
该死
Damn it.
别松手啊
Please don't drop me.
天啊 求你了 千万别松手啊
Oh, God, no. Please, please don't.
抱歉 来晚了
Sorry I'm late.
小心台阶
Watch your step.
行头不错嘛
Nice suit.
很帅嘛 闪电侠
Looking good, Flash.
谢
Oh, uh... Thank... Uh...
至于你
And you...
不用谢我
are welcome.
我天性自负 从来不会跟别人道谢
My ego's far too big to say "thank you" to someone else.
我把自己塑造成个狠角色
I developed this... all-powerful persona
是为了弥补童年创伤
to compensate for my childhood trauma...
我也有童年创伤
I, too, have childhood trauma.
真言套索
The Lasso of Truth...
总是很灵
...never gets old.
我还不如把自己的钱都捐出去
I'd do a lot better just giving all my money away.
消除犯罪的本质在于消除贫困
Yes, if I really wanted to end crime, I should end poverty.
我了解什么是亲热
I know sex exists.
我只是从没体验过而已
I've just never experienced it.
该死
Damn it.
我想
Well...
我该走了
I have to run.
好
Yeah.
不用客气
Always a pleasure.
我刚才只是想打个比方
The sex thing was a metaphor...
我想比喻的是哥特文学
for gothic literature.
根本就圆不回来了
There was just no way to recover from that.
别想了
Just let it go.
那个 我很想继续帮你收拾烂摊子
Well, I'd really love to stay and clean up more mess...
但我这个小超级英雄得去吃早饭了
but this little superhero needs his breakfast.
再见 闪电侠
Goodbye, Flash.
好吧 再见 蝙蝠侠
Yeah. Bye, Batman.
漂亮 韦恩先生
Well done, Mr. Wayne.
回家吃早饭吗 先生
Will you be home for breakfast, sir?
是的 我看行
Yes, I think so.
只会自取灭亡
...the road to destruction.
跟她有什么关系
This was never about her.
这是你自己的人生
This is about you.
一个人不能总是活在过去
You have to stop living in the past.
怎么样 我做得够快了吧
Now, was that fast enough for you?
（研究中心）
看看谁来了
Ah, look who's here.
闭嘴 阿尔伯特
Shut up, Albert.
整天迟到
Every day.
你怎么做到的 巴里
I don't know how you do it, Barry.
你是爬着来的吗 老兄
What'd you, like, crawl here, bro?
他生气了吗
Is he mad?
你饭碗要不保了
Well, you're getting fired.
小命都不保了
You're getting murdered.
先别解释
Oh, no, no, no.
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
你的闹钟没有响
Your alarm clock didn't go off.
不对 你的狗把闹钟吃了
-No-- -Oh, your dog ate your alarm clock.
你的闹钟把你的钥匙吃了
Your alarm clock ate your keys.
钥匙的奶奶去世了
Your keys' grandmother died,
所以它们都要请假
and they need a personal day.
那倒不至于
It was none of those things.
这次又有什么借口 巴里
What was it this time, Barry?
是有事耽搁了
It was, um, something else
但没您说的那么离谱
that was far less outlandish.
我知道我没赶上开会
And I know I missed the meeting...
但我还是想提交这些案件 看看能否再调查一下
but I'd still really like to present these case files for potential review.
我认为这些案件处理得太仓促了
I think we rushed these cases.
需要重新调查取证 仓促
-We need to reopen them. -Oh! Rushed?
我们已经积压了六个月的案件
We got a backlog six months deep,
你居然还想再慢一些吗
and you want us to move slower?
专注在那些要上庭的案件上
You need to focus your motion.
把手上的活儿干完 结案 然后继续
Do the work, close the case, move on.
你其实很有潜力 巴里
You have a lot of potential, Barry.
这么多年了 给我倒咖啡这种事早就不该你来做了
You shouldn't still be getting me coffee after all these years.
没错 您说得对
You're right. That's... That's true.
去给我倒杯咖啡
Go get me a coffee.
两块方糖 不然呢
Two sugars? Yeah.
好
Oh, yeah.
快来听好消息
You're gonna love this.
我对约翰逊一案的裁决感到满意
I'm very satisfied with the ruling in the Johnson case.
由我们的实验室所参与分析的证据
The evidence our lab analyzed...
足以给出充分的证明
was more than sufficient to be conclusive.
那些证据我还没分析完呢
-I'm still working that evidence. -Because of the diligence
而这要归功于我们工作人员的 辛勤付出和高度专注
and hard work and focus...
那些证据巴里还没分析完呢
Barry was still working on that evidence.
要是都听你的
Think if it were up to you
几十年前的杀人犯到现在都没法定罪
that we'd still be scraping Ted Bundy's molars.
我告诉你们 你们或许觉得这样的事情好笑
You know what? I'm so happy you find this all so hilarious,
但我们经手的可都是关乎人命的
but we are dealing with real people's lives,
他们可都有家庭
people's families.
你们根本认识不到事情的严重性
And I don't think you can grasp the gravity of that.
所以 别烦我了 行吗
So, why don't you leave me alone?
巴里艾伦
Barry Allen?
艾瑞斯韦斯特
Iris West.
你
You...
也知道我的全名
know my full name also.
我们是校友嘛
Yes, from school.
巴里 原来你还有学校的朋友啊
Aw, Barry, you didn't tell us you had a friend from school.
我们都不知道他居然还有朋友
We actually didn't know that Barry had a friend.
是啊 算算他有多少朋友
Yeah, what does that make it now?
一个
One?
一个 对
One.
你们俩真是
You guys are so...
再见 二位 好吧 再见
Um, bye, you guys.
知道了 我的天啊
Okay. Oh, my God.
我和他们俩并不熟 只是同事而已
That was just... They're not really my friends. They're my work friends.
你在这儿工作
Do you work here?
对 没错
Yes, I do.
真的好久没见了吧
God, it's been a long time, huh?
但我之前好像在哪儿见过你
I feel like we saw each other...
就前两年 对吗
like a few years ago, right?
没有 因为
No, because...
我们上一次见面还是在
we haven't seen each other since...
大学时
college.
也可能就是我想见你
Maybe I was just thinking about you.
不管怎样 很高兴能再遇到你
Well, I'm really glad I ran into you.
是吗 是啊
-Yeah. -Yeah.
你父亲的案子明天重审 对吧
Your father's appeal is tomorrow, right?
是 你怎么
Yeah. How...
抱歉 你是怎么知道的
Sorry, how do you know about that?
我在报社负责这篇报道
I'm covering it for the paper.
你父亲还好吗
How is he holding up?
这是采访的问题吗
Are you asking for the paper?
不是 是我作为朋友关心一下
No, I'm asking as a friend.
但我想公众肯定也会感兴趣的
Although I'm sure the public would want to know as well.
好吧
Well...
我只能告诉你 我爸爸是被冤枉的
my only official comment is that my dad is innocent.
当然
Right.
我是说 没有人
I mean, no one...
愿意相信自己的父亲会杀害自己的母亲
would want to believe that their father killed their mother.
什么叫相信 我爸爸根本就不该坐牢
What do you mean, "believe"? My dad shouldn't be in jail.
我妈妈也该活得好好的
My mom should be alive.
与我信不信无关
It's not about what I believe.
事实就是事实
It's about what the truth is.
当然 不 我是说
Right. No, yes, that's...
天啊 我本来就是这个意思
Oh, my God. That's what I meant.
好吧
Right.
抱歉 关于此案 我现在无可奉告
Sorry, I have no official comment at this time.
（机密物证 韦恩企业）
您有一通来自铁山监狱的
You have a collect call
（抱歉 布鲁斯韦恩）
对方付费电话
from the Iron Heights Penitentiary.
请问是否要接听
Do you wish to accept?
接听
Yes.
喂 爸爸
Hey, Dad.
喂 巴里
Hey, Barry.
你最近好吗
How ya doing?
挺好的
I'm fine.
有多出去走走吗
You getting out much?
有啊
Yeah.
好吧 没有
Well, no.
没有
Uh, no.
不过我碰到了一个大学时的朋友
But I, um, I ran into an old college friend...
艾瑞斯韦斯特 就今天
Iris West, today.
她不是你上学时的女神吗
Didn't you have a monster crush on her?
她现在有男朋友吗
Well, she have a boyfriend?
你怎么不约她出去
Why don't you ask her out?
爸爸 我
Dad, I, um...
我有个朋友帮忙 修复了那家超市以前的监控录像
I had a friend run the old security camera footage from the store...
用的是他研究的新程序
through this new program he's developed.
现在的画面很清晰
And it's crystal clear now.
只是
It's just...
你一直没抬头 爸爸
you never look up, Dad.
看不见你的脸
You can't see your face.
所以就没有新证据来支持你的不在场证明
So, without new evidence to support your alibi...
恐怕得开始研究下一次怎么上诉了
we're just gonna need to start thinking about the next appeal.
不 行了
No, uh-uh.
别再惦记着你老爸的事了
You need to stop worrying about your old man.
这样你才能有时间交女朋友啊
Do that, you might actually have time for a girlfriend.
可是 爸爸 我不想
But Dad, I don't want...
这条老路我们走过
We've done this before.
这已经是最后的努力了
This was a last-ditch effort...
明天就当是再走走过场
and we'll go through the motions tomorrow.
爸爸没事 真的
I'm okay, really.
要我说 我有时候觉得
You know, sometimes I even think
在牢里待着 反而对我来说更容易一些
it's probably easier for me to be in here
比起外面
than out there...
她不在了
without her.
在这儿还能有个念想 想象她还活着
'Cause this way, I can imagine she's alive...
好好地过日子
out there living her life.
巴里
Barry?
你还在吗
You there?
在呢 爸爸
Yeah, I'm here, Dad.
还记得她周日常做的那个酱汁吗
Hey, remember that sauce she'd make on Sundays?
满屋子都是罗勒草和西红柿的香味
The whole house would smell like basil, tomatoes.
她还喜欢穿我的衣服 边跳边唱
And she'd put on my sweats and start singing.
是啊 什么歌来着
Yeah, what was that song?
我喜欢那首歌
I loved that song.
牢记这些
Remember that part.
这不合理啊
It's not fair.
什么不合理 小猴子
What's not fair, Monkey?
这道题出得太蠢了
This question is stupid.
你能想出多少种计算结果为24的算法
How many calculations can you think of with an answer of 24?
这有无数种答案啊
There are a bajillion answers.
这怎么写得完啊
How am I supposed to fit them all?
你说得没错
You are right.
这个问题确实有无数种答案
There are a bajillion answers to this question.
有的问题注定无解
Not every problem has a solution.
有时候你得学会放弃
Sometimes you just have to let go.
让小脑瓜休息一下 来帮我做意面
Give your brain a rest and help me make the pasta.
快来
Come on.
不是吧
No.
（西班牙语）该死
亨利
Henry?
（西班牙语）怎么了 亲爱的
需要你帮我一个忙
I need you to do me a favor.
我不爱帮忙
I don't do favors.
好啊
Okay.
其实是巴里需要你帮忙
Barry needs you to do him a favor.
巴里啊 那没问题
Oh, Barry! Yeah, anything.
我还需要一罐西红柿
I need another can of tomatoes.
这不是有吗
You have a can of tomatoes.
还需要一罐
I need another one.
你们早上不是去超市了吗
I thought you guys went to the store this morning.
但是我忘买西红柿了
But I forgot the tomatoes.
我倒是有个更好的主意
This looks way more fun.
不如让巴里去一趟超市
Let's just let Barry go to the store.
你会开车 对吧 小鬼
You drive, right, Squirm?
当然不会 你都这么大了
-What? No. -Getting so big.
肯定没问题 看看你
You can do anything. Look at ya.
甚至都有白头发了
You're getting gray, actually.
买绿皮罐头的 别买成蓝皮的 好吗
Green can, not the blue one, okay?
知道了
Got it.
买蓝皮罐头的 别买成绿皮的 对吧
Blue can, not the green one, right?
错了
No!
什么 是绿皮的 不是蓝皮的
Green can, not the blue one. What?
完蛋了
Oh, God.
她要开始唱歌了
She's gonna start singing.
快跑
Run!
巴里 快跑
Run, Barry!
歌词大意 就让这些美妙的歌声 道出我的心声
生活真的会给人惊喜
天啊 生活真会给人惊喜
我爱你 小猴子
I love you, Monkey.
我爱你更多
I love you more.
我爱你更早
I loved you first.
诺拉
Nora?
巴里
Barry!
不 别动 亲爱的
别碰它 别乱动 好吗
巴里
Barry!
快打急救电话 快
Call 911 now!
巴里
Barry?
别为明天担心了
Don't worry about tomorrow.
我们早就知道机会渺茫
We always knew it was a long shot...
爸爸
Dad?
您与来自铁山监狱的通话已结束
Your call with Iron Heights Penitentiary has been terminated.
巴里艾伦
Barry Allen?
但我之前好像在哪儿见过你
由我们的实验室
...evidence our lab...
专注在那些要上庭的案件上
You need to focus your motion.
把手上的活儿干完 结案
Do the work...
怎么样 我做得够快了吧
Now, was that fast enough for you?
你是说 你回到了过去
So, you're saying you went back in time?
像在波扎尔诺夫那次
Like in Pozharnov?
没错 只不过那次只有一秒钟左右
Yeah, like in Pozharnov, except, but Pozharnov was a second.
而这次我回溯了一整天的时间
This time I went back a whole day.
那我们就假设
So, let's imagine...
你的确有可能跑得足够快
that it is, in fact, possible for you to run...
比光速还要快
faster than the speed of light...
通过那么做 你能回到过去
and in so doing, travel back in time.
可是那么做
It still would be...
真的很不负责任
wildly irresponsible.
料到你会这么说
I knew you were gonna say this.
是啊
Yes,
巴里 因为如果你回到过去
because, Barry, if you were to go into the past,
和你父母或是你自己的任何互动
any interaction you have with your parents or yourself,
哪怕只是走错一步路
you step on the wrong blade of grass,
都有可能产生你根本想象不到的严重后果
you have no idea what the consequences to that could be.
我知道 蝴蝶效应 对吧
No, I know. The butterfly effect, right?
没错
Yes.
我懂
I get it.
可是 布鲁斯 我能解决问题
But Bruce... I could fix things.
同时你也可能毁灭一切
You could also destroy everything.
我能救她
I could save her.
能让他俩都得救 甚至
I could save both of them. I...
还能救你的父母
I could save your parents.
巴里 正是这些伤痕
Barry, these scars we have...
造就了我们
make us who we are.
不要想着去修复它们
We're not meant to go back and fix them.
现在的你很好 不需要去修复什么
And there's nothing broken with you that needs to be fixed.
就听我这个过来人的经验之谈吧
Take it from an old guy who's made a lot of mistakes.
不要活在过去
Don't live your past.
活好当下
Live your life.
不要让悲剧定义你
Don't let your tragedy define you.
如果我注定要被定义呢
What if it's supposed to define me?
悲剧让你成了英雄
Your tragedy made you a hero.
也让我孤身一人
And also made me alone.
这不有我吗
We could hang out.
要不去吃点儿东西
I mean, do you wanna get a bite?
我还是很饿
Like, I'm still hungry.
这次就算了吧
Not this time.
下次再说吧
Maybe some other time.
好
Yeah.
车不错嘛
Nice ride.
你朋友很有钱嘛
You have fancy friends.
是我叫的网约车
Yeah, it was an Uber.
高端网约车
Exec.
艾瑞斯 我真不能和你聊案子的事
Look, Iris, I really can't talk about the case at all.
我此刻是朋友 不是记者
I'm not here as a reporter.
能聊聊吗
Can we talk?
请进
Come on in.
说实话 你这里比我想的整洁多了
I'm not gonna lie. It's a lot tidier in here than I expected.
是吗
Yeah?
是
Yeah, well, um...
那好吧 我是个很爱干净的人
Yeah. I'm a pretty tidy person.
喝点儿东西吗
Can I offer you a drink?
好啊
Sure.
来瓶啤酒吧
I'll take a beer.
啤酒 啤酒 啤酒
Beers, beers, beers.
就放在冰箱里
I keep 'em in my fridge.
谢谢
Thanks.
客气
Sure.
那个 对于我之前说的那些话
Look, I feel really bad
我很过意不去
about earlier.
我应该考虑到你的心情
I should've been more sensitive.
我也许也不该那么敏感的
And, um, I probably could've been less sensitive.
我无法想象你都经历了什么
I mean, I can't imagine what you've been through.
几乎在同一天失去了双亲
It's like you lost both parents in one day.
的确是
I did.
母亲死于一场悲剧
I lost my mom to a tragedy,
而司法系统的漏洞又让我失去了父亲
and I lost my dad to the failures of the justice system.
所以你去了刑事取证部门
Is that why you got into criminal forensics?
试图修复司法系统
To try and fix the system?
是的
Yeah.
没错 修复
Yeah, to fix it.
肯定有办法修复 对吧
There's gotta be a way to fix it, right?
其实这也是我从事新闻业的原因
I mean, that's kinda why I got into journalism, too.
只要我能回到过去 我就能找到办法
I could make it right if I could just go back somehow
在他们不知情的状态下 给他们警告
and warn them without them knowing that I'd warned them.
你这么想
I... thinking like that's gonna...
会把自己逼疯的
...drive you crazy.
如果我能回到过去
"If I could just go back in time...
阻止凶手行凶就好了 这
and stop the guy who did it." It's...
不行 要是那么做 动静就太大了
No, I can't do that, 'cause that's way too much interaction.
我爸爸当时根本就不在家
My dad wasn't even at home.
因为我妈妈让他去买西红柿了
My mom sent him to go get a can of tomatoes.
当年那个歹徒可能以为家里没人
I think whoever broke into the house thought it was empty.
直到看见了我妈妈 她手里有刀
And then my mom was in there with the knife in her hand
于是情况变糟 看似荒谬的事接连发生
and things went bad, just this absurd chain of events.
这段录像本应成为我爸爸的不在场证明的
And it's like, this footage should've finally supported my dad's alibi.
然而却
But instead...
一罐西红柿毁了三个人的一生
three lives ruined for a can of tomatoes.
天啊
Oh, my God.
怎么
What?
有突破点了
Well, that could be it.
要是妈妈没忘买西红柿
If my mom doesn't forget the tomatoes in the first place,
爸爸就不会出门 妈妈也就不会死
then he never leaves and she never dies.
我不需要露面
No one would even have to see me.
这样也就没有布鲁斯说的互动
Bruce said no interaction. This is no interaction.
我可以快进快出
This is just quick in, quick out,
回到现在 跟从来没回去过一样
back to the present, like I was never even there.
就这么办 天啊 艾瑞斯
That's how I fix it. Oh, my God, Iris.
太感谢你了
Thank you, so much.
真是太好了
This has been great.
实在抱歉
I'm sorry.
我得走了
I... I have to leave.
好的 好
Okay. Right.
对了 聊得很开心 改天再约
I had a really great time, by the way. We should do this again.
卡尔-艾尔 氪星之子
Kal-El, son of Krypton.
这个主意糟透了
This is a bad idea.
看来你很快
So, you're fast.
你爸爸是个杀人犯
Your dad's a murderer.
（诺拉艾伦 爱妻与慈母）
快打急救电话 快
Call 911 now!
快
...now!
（西红柿罐头）
嗨 妈妈
Hi, Mom.
别忘了这罐西红柿
Don't forget the tomatoes.
回头见
See you soon.
要成功啊
Please work.
祝你生日快乐
? Happy Birthday, dear... ?
生日快乐 巴里
Happy Birthday, Barry.
加油 巴里 冲啊 加油
- Go, Barry, hurry up. - Go!
2013届的毕业生们 祝你们毕业快乐
Congratulations to the class of 2013!
妈妈好爱你
好爱你 妈妈好爱你
I love you so much.
（西班牙语）吓我一跳
小猴子
Monkey!
你穿的什么呀
What are you wearing?
巴里回来了 这么早
Is that Barry? And he's early?
太阳打西边出来了
What universe is this?
你剪头发了
You've cut your hair.
这下能看见眼睛了
Now you can see your eyes.
怎么变丑了
You look terrible.
亨利
Henry!
看着老了 我儿子多帅啊
-You look old. -You look beautiful, baby.
你在学校到底经历了什么
What are they doing to you over there?
别说了 我儿子多棒啊
Leave him alone. He's perfect.
来 抱抱
Come here.
我好爱你
I love you so much.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
我爱你更多
I love you more.
我爱你更早
I loved you first.
去洗个澡 换身衣服
Go take a shower and change.
一身臭鞋子味儿
You smell like a boot.
快去 快去
Go, go, go.
老了
"Old,"
真有你的
seriously?
好吧 我是说成熟了
Well, no, I mean like mature.
他这个年纪 看着成熟点儿好
He's at that age, he wants to look old.
比如 能混进酒吧
He, you know, gets into bars that way.
需要帮忙吗
How can I help?
妈妈 今天过得好吗
Hey, Mom, how was your day?
这个月 还有过去18年 都还好吗
How was your month, or your last 18 years?
好奇怪的问题
Or that's a weird question...
因为我也在
'cause I was here.
很明显 这些事我应该都记得才对
But obviously, we share those memories together.
要不 我们去创造些新的回忆
Or I don't know, maybe we could make some new memories.
比如去水族馆 或者马戏团
Like we could go to the aquarium, or the circus,
公园也行 你们可以推我荡秋千
or to the park and you could push me on a swing.
也好奇怪 因为我已经是成年人了
That's also weird because I'm an adult now,
完全可以自己荡秋千了
so I'd probably motivate my own motion on a swing.
对了 这周在学校过得怎么样啊
So, how was it this week? How's school?
在学校 我过得好着呢
At school was... is good.
一切都好
School's been great.
我有好好学习 学我的那些
I've just been working really hard there on my...
专业课
studies.
约经济学课上那个姑娘了吗
Did you ask out that girl from econ?
我知道大一新生通常应该
I know freshman year is about
多参加活动 结识新朋友
going out, meeting people, okay?
还有多探索
Exploring things.
多尝试新鲜事物
Experimenting.
但是 还是要多谨慎一点儿
But you have to be very careful.
糟了
Oh, shit.
我突然想上厕所
I... have to shit.
我去了
Outside.
救命
Help!
你怎么在这儿
Why are you here?
今年是哪年
What year is it?
别乱动 救命
-No, no, no. -Help!
这是我的脸
That's my face.
你偷了我的脸
You stole my face.
是致幻蘑菇导致的吗
Think I'm having a mushroom flashback?
有可能吗
Is that a thing?
你多大了
How old are you?
18岁
Eighteen.
这也太魔幻了
This is mad trippy.
那我们这是在未来
So, we're, like, in the future.
不是 等一下
No, wait.
一点儿也不魔幻 老弟
This is not trippy, dude.
简直是飞来横祸
This is catastrophic.
这也不是未来
And no, we're not in the future.
我本该回到原来的时空
I was supposed to be back in the present,
但我还在过去
but I'm still in the past.
不应该有两个我
And there's not supposed to be two of me.
你和我不该出现在同一个时空里
You and I are not supposed to be occupying the same reality at all,
更不该像这样互动
let alone interacting.
真不敢相信我是个能够穿越时空的超级英雄
I just can't believe I'm a superhero who time travels--
不 你还什么都不是
No, no, no. You are not anything.
这是好事
Which is good.
你不会想当超级英雄的 太可怕了
You don't want to be a superhero. It's scary.
而且跑起来时 牙缝里全是小虫子
And I get bug splatter in my teeth all the time.
厉害
Awesome.
再表演一遍
Hey, do the thing again.
不行 没时间了
No, we don't have time.
妈妈
Mom!
你干吗 还想告状
What are you doing? You're gonna tattle now?
再来一遍
Do the thing.
好吧
Fine.
爽
Yeah. Yeah.
满意了吗
Happy?
满意了 再放回去
Now undo it.
好疼
Ow.
巴里 你在楼上没事吧
Barry, are you okay up there?
我们没事
We're fine!
我没事
I'm fine! Okay, Monkey.
你们有可以水下飞行的飞机了吗
So, do you have like a plane that goes underwater?
天上飞的船呢
Or like a boat that can fly?
你多大 40岁
How old are you, like 40?
喂 你话怎么这么多
Okay, you don't stop talking.
太不讨喜了
It's not charming.
既不中听 还让人心累
It's abrasive and exhausting.
我的天啊
And, oh, my God.
我才知道我原来这么讨人厌
I am starting to realize what people mean.
就当
Just...
帮我个忙
do me a favor
跟我保证 我们的见面不会破坏时空秩序
and promise me that meeting me isn't gonna screw up space-time.
好兄弟
Broski...
我保证
I got you.
糟了 这下我麻烦大了
Shit, I'm in so much trouble.
什么意思
What do you mean?
怎么办
What do I do?
给你下药
I could drug you.
对 迷晕你
Yeah, I could drug you,
等你再醒来的时候
and then you'd pass out, you'd wake up
就会忘记这一切
and you'd forget that anything ever happened.
这么做没毛病吧 因为我们是同一人
And it wouldn't be wrong, right? Because you're me.
不行 我是说 不能这么做
No! I mean, we shouldn't.
拜托你不要
Please don't...
给我下药
drug me.
不行
No.
不行 因为我已经仔细想过了
No. Because here's the thing, and I thought about it before.
我可不想被下药
I don't want to be drugged.
但我们肯定还有别的办法
But I'm sure we can think of another way.
我们打开脑洞 好好想想
Let's put on our Barry thinking caps
肯定有别的办法
and think of a different solution
能让我失忆
for memory loss.
还有 我练过巴西战舞 已经绿带了
Also, I'm a green belt... in the capoeira,
我还仔细研究过格斗摔跤
and I have extensively studied wrestler,
你要真对我动手 肯定会吃大亏的
and I could just go frickin' lunatic on you.
何况 我今晚还有约会
Besides, I have a date tonight...
那好
Okay.
要多大力气才能把他打到失忆
How hard do you have to hit someone to make them forget stuff?
打过去的自己 未来的我会受伤吗
If I hit you in the past, will it hurt me in the future?
等等 你今晚有约会
Wait. You say you have a date tonight?
是啊 你刚刚想干什么
Yeah. Wait, what were you doing?
没什么
Uh, nothing.
跟谁约会
Who's your date with?
经济学课同班的一个大美女
This super babe in my econ class.
艾瑞斯韦斯特
Iris West?
老的天啊
Oh, my God!
我们会娶她
Do we marry her?
你今晚要去和她约会
You're going on a date with her tonight?
所以我回来让妈妈帮忙洗衣服
That's why I need Mom to do my laundry.
连自己的衣服都不洗
You don't even do your own laundry?
你呢
Do you?
好吧
Okay.
我真得走了
I'm actually gonna go.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
好好过日子 做自己
Enjoy your life. Do you.
什么都别改变
Change literally nothing.
走了 再也不见
Um, I'll see you again never.
可我还有几个问题
I have a few more questions, though.
我们还有很多事没弄清楚
We have so much to learn from each other.
真是的
Oh, great.
你要拍屁股走人
Well, you're leaving me.
雨把我的约会也毁了
And now the storm's gonna ruin my date.
今天是哪天
What day is it today?
星期天吧
Sunday?
不 日期
No, the date.
9月29日
It's September 29th.
该死
Shit.
这场暴风雨 就是这一天
This storm, this is the day.
哪一天
What day?
我获得超能力的那天
The day I got my powers.
你获得超能力的这天
The day you get your powers.
超能力
Powers?
听着
Listen...
我不能告诉你 我为什么回到过去
I can't tell you why I traveled back in time,
也不能告诉你 我改变了什么
and I can't tell you what I changed.
总之就是在我的时空里
But, essentially, in my version of reality,
我上大一时 在中心城的犯罪实验室实习
I ended up interning at the Central City Crime Lab in my freshman year,
就是在那里发生的
and that's where it happened.
将要发生
Well, happens.
就今晚 9月29日
Tonight, September 29,
那场意外给了我超能力
the accident that gives me my powers.
要是你没在那儿
And if you're not there...
只剩半小时了
in 30 minutes...
你就无法获得超能力
then you won't get the powers.
也就是说 我也有可能无法获取超能力
Which means I don't get the powers, maybe?
如果这样的话 我从一开始就不可能
And then, that would mean that I lose my way
穿越时空 回到过去
of getting back in time in the first place,
之后会发生什么 我就真的不知道了
and then I literally have no idea what happens.
超能力
Powers?
等等 那约会怎么办
Wait, but what about our date tonight?
她可能是我们未来的妻子啊
She might be our future wife.
要是你现在不跟我走的话
There might not be a future...
可能就没有未来了
if you don't come with me...
就现在
right now.
（中心城 研究中心）
还有八分钟
Eight minutes.
我们要怎么进去
How are we gonna to get inside?
你要干吗
What are you doing?
能少说两句吗
Would you stop whining?
接下来的感觉会有点儿怪
This is gonna feel kinda weird.
就这么穿过来了
We walk through the door.
没错 靠的是神速力共振
Yes, it's okay. It's called phasing.
走吧
Come on.
太过瘾了
I love phasing.
我们走 紧紧跟在我后面
Everybody moves.
好
Well...
就是这儿
this is it.
我当时就坐在这里
This is where I was sitting.
对了 来 我先帮你放一边
And actually, let me take this for you.
谢啦
Thank you.
我想想 当时 我打开的是那扇窗户
Okay, I had just opened those windows...
为的是给室内通通风
to clear out the fumes.
快到时间了
Right around now.
当时 我坐在这把椅子上
And I was sitting in that chair,
就坐在这排架子前面
and I was right under this shelf of chemicals.
然后 闪电就劈了进来
And that's when the lightning hits.
等等
Wait.
我会被闪电劈中
I get hit by lightning?
不 不 不
No, no, no.
你不会被闪电劈中
You don't get hit by lightning.
好吧 有一瞬间我还以为
Okay, 'cause for a second I thought you said...
闪电会劈中化学试剂
The lightning hits the chemicals...
然后把它们溅到你身上
which then you get bathed in,
导致你被电击
and that's what electrocutes you.
什么 我可不想被电死
Okay, but I don't want to be electrocuted, though.
坐好别动
Sit down.
该坐好的是你 我已经有超能力了
-No, you sit down. -I already have the powers!
你已经有超能力了
You already have the powers!
就是啊
Exactly!
我才不想被雷劈
I am not getting struck by lightning!
成功了
It worked.
你好像掉了一颗牙
It looks like you lost a tooth.
没有
No?
是你掉的
You lost a tooth.
（胶水）
好了 我们撤
All right. We gotta go.
出什么事了
What have we got?
无菌实验室的警报响了
The alarms in the sterile lab.
去检查一下
Go check it.
去门口守着
Securing the entrance.
得穿出去
We've gotta phase.
共振 共振
Phase, phasing.
该死
Shit!
我变慢了
I'm slow.
你这儿怎么比我想象的整洁那么多
Why is your place so much nicer than I expected it to be?
喜欢吗 妈妈帮着收拾的
You like it? Mom had to help decorate.
你是了解她的
You know Mom.
对 确实 她就这样
Right, yeah. Classic Mom.
她就这样
Classic Mom.
今天可真刺激
What a day.
巴里 那场意外给了你超能力
Barry, the accident gave you powers,
也夺走了我的超能力
but took mine away.
所以我不知道该怎么回去了
So, I don't know how I get back.
如果用不了神速力
Without access to the Speed Force,
我都不知道该怎么离开这里
I don't know how I ever leave.
你明白我的意思吗
Do you understand what I'm saying?
我可能被困住了
I might be stuck.
等一下
Wait.
我有超能力了
I have powers now?
对 但是
Yeah, but...
你 不不不
you... No, no, no.
这也太棒了
Holy speedballs.
听着 我知道你现在一定很激动
Okay, I know this is incredibly exciting,
因为我就是过来人 像飞毛腿冈萨雷斯一样
because I went through it. Speedy Gonzales!
是的 我自己也玩过很多次
Yes, I've done it many times myself.
但是你不能一上来就
You can't just start...
该死
Shit.
歌词大意 我们年轻
? We are young,
充满活力
we run green ?
保持牙齿
? Keep our teeth
干净整齐
Nice and clean ?
问亲访友
? See our friends
出游观光
See the sights ?
感觉挺好的
? And feel all right ?
弄点小钱
? Got some cash
买辆小车
Bought some wheels ?
开车出门
? Took it out
穿越原野
'Cross the fields ?
车子失控
? Lost control,
撞到墙上
hit a wall ?
我们挺好的
? But we're all right ?
我的天
Oh, my...
（坦纳烟花爆竹公司）
我马上走 我马上走
Okay, I'm leaving!
举起手来
Put your hands up.
你干什么了
What did you do?
没干什么
Nothing.
怎么了
Why?
巴里
Barry...
我刚才没跟你说衣服的事
I could've told you about the clothes.
摩擦生热
It's friction.
你跑得太快 普通衣服是会烧坏的
You run too fast, and regular fabrics are gonna burn up.
同理 不能在超光速状态下
It's the same reason why you can't
把人移得太远
move people very far at hyperspeed.
西兰花好像坏了
That broccoli looks rotten.
听好 有些东西是可以在超光速下移动的
Look, some things you can move.
比如 你可以移动
Like, you can move,
微波炉
for instance, a microwave.
有些就绝对不能移动 比如
But you can't move something like, say...
小宝宝
a baby.
巴里 我好像从来没吃过这么好的东西
Barry, it's like I've never eaten anything before.
味道特别 特别鲜活
Everything has this vivid flavor. Try a little.
尝一口 就一小口
Just take a little bite.
是不是很难吃
That's bad, isn't it?
当然很不好吃
Yeah, this is not good.
对 我逗你的
No, I was kidding.
我好厉害 我们都好厉害
I'm amazing. We're amazing.
我好饿
I'm so hungry.
等一下
Hey, wait.
我想试试那个共振
I wanna try that phasing thing.
那是怎么个振法
How do I do that?
先等等 没到时候呢 好吗
You don't. Not yet. Okay?
共振非常复杂
It's very complicated.
要练很长时间
Takes a long time
才能在身体整个加速的同时
to train your body to be able to speed up
让身上分子的振动速度放慢
whilst your molecules slow down enough to pass through
穿过固体的分子结构
the molecular structure of solid objects...
快给我滚出去
Get out of here!
你得先学会让我把话说完
You've gotta start letting me finish my sentences.
我们是一直这样又困 又饿
Are we always this sleepy? And hungry
还没衣服穿吗
and naked?
前两条 是的
Well, the first two, yes.
第三条 不是 我已经有办法了
The third one, no. I've figured that part out.
实话告诉你 如果教你这些
And honestly, if we're gonna do this
我有很多东西得跟你解释
there's a lot I'm gonna have to explain to you.
我觉得从这里开始讲比较好 就是
So, a good place to start, I guess, is that,
对 最初的战服
yeah, the original suit
是用一种复合材料制成
- was actually made out of this polysynth...
或者 那就
Or we'll
明天再继续说吧
pick this up tomorrow.
你是说 战服在戒指里
So, the suit is inside the ring?
对
Yeah.
真的
What?
这个是送我了吗
And I can have this?
不 不是送你
No, you can't have it.
是借给你
You can borrow it
免得你让自己的超能力害死
so you don't kill yourself using your powers.
（黑暗语）至尊戒 驭众戒
你按下这个按钮以后
You're gonna push this button
蚕丝分子会展开
and the silk molecules are gonna uncoil,
吸收大气中的气体
absorbing atmospheric gases
把战服完全撑开
and expanding the suit to full size.
准备好了吗
Ready?
它出来的时候可真小啊
It was so tiny...
你应该在它落地前就穿好它
You're supposed to put it on before it hits the floor.
我要 在你面前穿吗
What, like change... right here in front of you?
这附近根本就没有别人 巴里
There's no one even here anyway, Barry.
快点儿
Come on--
天啊
Whoo, man.
好紧
Tight.
有点疼
It hurts.
知道是哪儿疼吗
You know where it hurts?
那里疼
In my dick.
好了 我懂 我懂
Okay. I know, I know,
但我不想知道
but I don't need to know.
好了 我能继续了吗
Sorry, can we move on?
我是这么想的
Here's what I'm thinking.
只要我能教会你像我那样移动
If I can train you to move like I do,
我们就能重建时空之碗
then we can re-create the Chronobowl.
时空之碗
Chronobowl?
用神速力
In the Speed Force.
神速力
Speed Force?
这样 也许我就能找出办法 回到未来
And then maybe we can find some way to get me back to the future.
《回到未来》
Back to the Future.
好看 艾瑞克斯托罗兹
Yes! Eric Stoltz
在里面演得特别好
is chur boy in that movie.
他把角色完全演活了
What an embodied performance.
是迈克尔J福克斯吧
You mean Michael J. Fox?
《回到未来》吗
Back to the Future?
对 就是电影《回到未来》 天啊
- Yeah, in the movie Back to the Future? -  -Oh, my God!
怎么回事 不知道
-What's going on? -I don't know.
你得先把战服脱了
You need to take the suit off now.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
目击者表示
...reported seeing a mysterious object
澳大利亚海岸上空悬停着一枚神秘物体
hovering above the Australian seaboard.
（突发新闻 神秘物体悬停于地面上空）
以下是本台取得的录像片段 佐德
-We've obtained footage from the sighting and as you can see, the object... -Zod.
“糟的”
"Zod"?
什么“糟的”
What's a zod?
美国政府官员称
According to US government officials,
基于卫星数据显示
satellite data
这是一艘宇宙飞船
has confirmed the presence of a spacecraft.
我们会跟进
We'll be sure--
你们可以叫我佐德将军
My name is General Zod.
我的星球离地球非常遥远
I come from a world far from yours.
你们的星球长久以来
For some time, your world
庇护了我们的一位公民 糟了
-has sheltered one of my citizens. -No, no, no.
我要求你们立刻 这不可能
-This can't be happening. -I request that you return this individual...
把这个人送回来交给我看管 偏偏在这个时候
- Not now. - ...to my custody.
出什么事了
What's happening?
佐德在找超人
Zod's looking for Superman.
什么超人
What's a superman?
超人是生活在地球上的外星人
Superman is an alien who lives on Earth.
我猜他还在隐藏身份
I'm assuming still incognito.
不过 他是外星人
But, yeah, he's an alien,
非常非常厉害
and he's very powerful,
人也特别好
and he's just the best.
佐德和超人来自同一个星球
And then Zod is an alien from the same planet,
他也很厉害
also very powerful,
但他是个大坏蛋
but he's just the worst.
而当时 佐德就是来找克拉克的
And Zod came here to find Clark.
等等 克拉克又是谁
Wait, who's Clark?
克拉克就是超人
Clark is Superman.
好的
Oh. Okay.
然后 佐德
But then Zod
还想用他的创世引擎彻底改造地球的生态
also tried to terraform the planet with this World Engine thing,
最后超人阻止了他 可是在那之前
and Superman stopped him eventually,
佐德已经杀死了好多好多人
but not before Zod killed thousands of people.
天啊 在那个时候
-Yeesh. -And at the time,
我什么都做不了 我
there was nothing I could do, I've...
等等
Wait, you...
你 你当时在场
You were there?
对 当时我刚刚获得超能力
Yeah, I had just gotten my powers.
还在对战服做最后的修改
And I was still putting some finishing touches on my suit.
佐德的创世引擎
This thing, Zod's World Engine,
当时已经开始摧毁大都会了
it started destroying Metropolis,
所以我就赶了过去
so I just went there
想要救人
and I started trying to save people.
爸爸
Daddy?
听话 快跑啊
Listen to me! Run away!
快跑啊
Run away!
那个孩子
There was this kid, and I...
我救了他 可
I got him, but then...
我没法再救他爸爸
I couldn't get his dad.
爸爸
Daddy!
当年 我只有能力救那个孩子
It was all I could do, save that one kid.
只有超人能够阻止佐德
Only Superman could stop Zod.
可他也没来得及救那些人
But not in time to save those people.
现在 同样的事情又要重演了
And now it's about to happen again.
不过
But...
如果我能集结整个正义联盟
if I can find the entire Justice League,
就是超人和其他的英雄
Superman and the rest of the band...
对
Right.
也许我就能阻止这些事情的发生
...then maybe I can prevent the whole thing from ever even happening at all.
把你的电脑给我
Um, give me your laptop.
好的
Okay.
什么味道
What is that smell?
有味道的东西多了
Could be anything.
真的
Honestly.
那是谁
Who's that?
那是加里
That's Gary.
是他身上的味道
That's the smell. It's...
没事 他这人就是很随意
Don't worry. He's breezy.
一定能查到的
We can do this.
我看看
Uh, let's see,
维克多斯通 哥谭城市大学
Victor Stone, Gotham City University.
这位是我室友 帕蒂
Oh, this is my roommate, Patty.
帕蒂 是你室友
Patty... is your roommate?
那是她男朋友阿尔伯特
And that's her boyfriend, Albert.
你好啊
What's up?
早上好
Good morning.
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
那个 各位
And, uh, guys...
这位是我表哥
This is my cousin.
巴里
Barry.
我饿死了
I'm starving.
好吧
Okay.
维克多斯通 哥谭城市大学
Victor Stone, Gotham City University.
很好 就是他
Yes. Here he is.
（维克多斯通 骑士队明星四分卫）
骑士队明星四分卫 维克多斯通将迎来创纪录之年
Victor Stone, star quarterback for the Knight...
该死 好吧
Shit, okay.
他还没有变成钢骨
He's not Cyborg yet.
神奇女侠
Wonder Woman.
Wonder Woman!
拉斯维加斯常驻表演
Las Vegas residency.
（神奇女侠 新演出 拉斯维加斯常驻表演）
魔术 杂耍和斑马秀
Illusions, juggling, and zebras.
不对 这不是戴安娜
No. That is not Diana.
海王
Aquaman.
海王 这是一种
Aquaman? Is that like
超级人鱼吗
a super mermaid?
错 阿尔伯特 不是超级人鱼
No, Albert, he's not a super mermaid.
好吗
Okay?
他是亚特兰蒂斯人和人类生的混血儿
He's half Atlantean, half human
力量超凡
with superhuman strength
能用意念控制海洋生物
who can control marine life with his mind.
那不就是超级人鱼
So, like a super mermaid?
错 阿尔伯特
No, Albert!
你说的就是这个意思
That is what you described.
我来搜一下亚瑟库瑞
We'll just try Arthur Curry...
缅因的
Maine...
灯塔
lighthouse.
找到了
Here we are.
托马斯库瑞 这是他爸爸
Thomas Curry. That's his dad.
电话给我
Uh, phone.
你好
Hello.
您好 是托马斯库瑞吗
Hello, Thomas Curry?
是
Yes.
我能找下亚瑟吗 亚瑟在家吗
Could I speak to Arthur? Is Arthur around?
你想找我家的狗
You wanna speak to my dog?
什么
What?
不 不
No, no.
抱歉
Um, sorry. Uh...
您是托马斯库瑞吗
Is this Thomas Curry?
是啊
Yes.
您在灯塔工作
And you work at a lighthouse?
是啊
Yes.
好的 您爱人是
Okay, and your wife
亚特兰蒂斯女王吗
is the queen of Atlantis?
不是
Uh, no.
好 或者说 她是不是一位
Uh, right, but maybe, maybe...
像鱼一样的女士
um, a fishlike woman
有一天搁浅在了岸边
washed into your life
进入了你的生活呢
at some point or another?
你可真幽默 混球
Very funny, asshole.
亚瑟库瑞根本没出生
Arthur Curry was never born.
什么
What?
简直是一场灾难 我
This is a disaster. I-I-
彻底扰乱了历史
I completely destroyed history.
就像艾瑞克斯托罗兹
Like Eric Stoltz.
我说 你怎么老提这个人的名字
Okay, why do you keep saying, "Eric Stoltz"?
他演了马蒂麦克弗莱
Eric Stoltz is Marty McFly.
什么
What?
时间旅行
Time travel?
你们在聊《回到未来》
We talking "BTTF"?
喂 这人到底是谁
Come on, who is this guy?
不是 我知道
Okay, yeah, no, I know.
我把《回到未来》全看了
I've seen all of them
马蒂麦克弗莱不是艾瑞克斯托罗兹演的
and Eric Stoltz is not Marty McFly.
是吗
Really?
那这个麦克“股”莱怎么解释
Then explain Marty McThigh here.
没法跟你解释 加里
I can't explain that to you, Gary.
那儿可不是“股”
That's not your thigh.
演员也纹错了 还上下颠倒了
It's the wrong actor, and it's upside down.
是吗
Is it?
可重点在于
The point is that
在《回到未来》里
in Back to the Future
大家都知道 演这个角色的人
Marty McFly is very famously played
是迈克尔J福克斯
by Michael J. Fox.
演《浑身是劲》的那个
The guy from Footloose?
错 那是凯文培根
No, that's Kevin Bacon!
培根
Bacon.
培根演了独行侠
Kevin Bacon's Maverick
打排球 秀肌肉 开飞机的那个
with the volleyball, the gay guys, and the planes?
《壮志凌云》
Top Gun.
“熊熊的烈火” 《壮志凌云》
? Great balls of fire! ? Top Gun, right?
完了 完了 对吧
No, no, no.
我把整个宇宙都给搅乱了
I completely broke the universe.
斯托罗兹演了麦克弗莱
Marty McFly is Eric Stoltz.
对了
Yes.
谢了
Thank you.
我制造了一个没有超人类的世界
I created a world with no metahumans.
这下没人帮我们抵挡佐德了
And now there's no one to defend us from Zod.
阿尔伯特
Albert!
这里没有钢骨
There's no Cyborg.
也没有海王 没有神奇女侠
There's no Aquaman. There's no Wonder Woman.
没有超人
There's no Superman.
没有蝙蝠侠
There's no Batman.
我是蝙蝠侠
I'm Batman.
你 你刚才说什么来着
What, you... What did you just say?
我是蝙蝠侠
I'm Batman.
这儿有蝙蝠侠
Batman exists?
当然了
Hundo p.
是啊 兄弟 没人知道他的真实身份
Yeah, dude. Nobody knows who he really is,
不过 是有这么个人
but he exists.
好
Right.
好吧 我们
Well, uh, we...
我和巴里表弟
my cousin Barry and I,
要去另一位表哥家吃饭了
have to go to that cousin's dinner.
现在就得走
Now.
不过还是很高兴认识大家
But it was a pleasure to meet you all.
再见 加里
And Gary. Barry.
再见 巴里
Gary. Barry.
-Barry. -Gary.
再见 加里
Gary. Barry.
巴里
Barry!
你是在逗我吧 这是什么鬼地方
What, are you frickin' kidding me with this place?
这是哪儿 地狱吗
What is this, hell?
门没关
It's open.
快看 这些东西好酷
Look at all this cool shit!
行了 巴里 不要碰这里的东西
Okay, Barry, don't touch anything in here.
有人吗
Hello?
布鲁斯
Bruce?
布鲁斯 你在吗
Bruce, are you there?
好家伙
Oh, boy.
我都不知道你会画画
Hey, I didn't know you painted.
画得挺好
They're good.
布鲁斯韦恩
Bruce Wayne?
布鲁斯
Bruce?
你看这里
Hey, check this out.
这些铃铛连着这里的各个房间
There's, like, bells connected to every room in this house.
没准我们摇摇铃
Hey, maybe we can find this Bruce guy...
就能找到这位布鲁斯 你说呢
if we just ring all these bells, right?
你不知道仆人铃怎么用吗
You don't understand how servant bells work?
是其他房间里的人摇铃召唤这里的人
You ring them from all the other places.
是吗
What?
你们这边没有《唐顿庄园》吗
You don't have, like, Downton Abbey in your universe?
“糖炖庄园”
Downtown Abbey's?
你说那个连锁家常菜馆啊
The chain of, like, family-style restaurants?
就是个价位低一些的香蕉蜂
They're like, it's like cheaper Bananabee's.
知道我现在特想吃什么吗
Oh, you know what I'd really go for right now?
糖炖家的焦香西葫芦块
Abbey's sizzlin' zucchini squares.
行吧
Okay.
你有完没完
You know what, man?
真是受够你了
I've had it with you.
好了 暂停
什么啊
你是什么人
Who the hell are you?
我是这儿的主人
I'm the guy who lives here.
我们在找布鲁斯韦恩
We're looking for Bruce Wayne.
你们饿吗
You hungry?
佐德将军播报后
...following the broadcast earlier from General Zod.
（重要新闻 外星人播报引发公众恐慌）
他们寻找的目标依然没有音讯
The individual they're searching for is still at large.
所以说
So...
你和他是同一个人
...you're the same person as him...
但你来自另一条时间线
but from an alternate timeline.
是的
Yes.
在你那边
In which...
我们是好朋友
you and I are friends?
对 你可能
Yeah, you're like
是我最好的朋友
probably my best friend.
好吧
Okay.
但是你有点 你
Well, but you're a bit... you're, uh...
你的岁数有些 变化
chronologically different.
老了
Older.
这也正是我弄不明白的地方
That's what I can't understand.
我回到了过去 从这里回到这里
I traveled back in time from here to here.
结果不知道为什么 我回到了
Yet somehow, everything's all changed
这里
back here.
或者是你出生的时候
Or like when you were born, so...
时间不是线性的 对吧
Well... time isn't linear. Right?
对
Right.
你可能
At some point
在电影里看到过这样的内容
you probably saw a movie that told you
如果你回到过去 改变了历史
that if you went back and changed the past,
就会创造出一条时间线分支 对不对
you'd create a kind of a branched timeline, right?
你看
Like, look.
新的当下
New present
新的未来
and new future.
对
Yeah.
时间不是这么运转的
Well, time doesn't work like that.
不是这个原理
That's not how time works.
你穿越回去 改变历史 就会创造出
When you go back and change the past
一个支点
you create a fulcrum.
你来到了一根新的意面上
You put yourself on a whole nother strand of spaghetti.
新的未来
New future.
新的过去
New past.
这是逆因果
It's retrocausal.
可以有两种走向
It goes both ways.
实际上 是有很多种走向
Actually, it goes many ways.
下次再说吧
Maybe some other time.
好吧 但是在本体论悖论模型里 并没有
Okay, but in an ontological paradox model, there's not...
你这样做 不但改变了未来
What you did was you changed the future
也改变了过去
and you changed the past.
倘若有人真的蠢到了家
If a person is stupid enough
扰乱了时间秩序
to mess with time...
最后就会导致
what you eventually end up with
这样的结果
is this.
多重宇宙
The multiverse.
有些时间线近乎平行
Some strands run almost parallel.
它们之间难免会有交汇点
There will be inevitable intersections,
其他时间线就会
and others that are just...
发散得很厉害
wildly divergent.
总之就是
What it is...
一团糟
is a hot mess.
就像掷骰子
It's a crapshoot.
完全没有规律可言
It's all just a crapshoot.
那干酪又代表什么
What does the parmesan mean?
他打完比方了 就是弄点装饰
The metaphor's over. It's just a garnish.
我就这么说吧
And I'll tell ya something.
只有那种特别特别蠢的人
A person would have to be an idiot
才会扰乱
to play craps
时空连续统
with the space-time continuum.
对 蠢
Yeah, an idiot.
给
Here.
你吃饭怎么会闹出这么大的动静
Are you joking with the chewing noises right now?
所以说
So, uh,
是因为你
you're the reason
这个叫佐德的家伙
this Zod character
才要毁灭地球
is about to destroy the Earth?
有可能
Maybe.
还有个叫超人的家伙
There's a guy called Superman
可以阻止佐德
who can stop Zod?
对 对
Yeah, yeah.
他还会飞
And flies?
还长着镭射眼
Shoots lasers out of his eyes?
没错 他会飞
Yes, he flies,
还长着镭射眼 没错
and he shoots lasers out of his eyes. Yes.
没人觉得超人这名号
No one said "Superman"...
有点太刻意了吗
that might be a little on the nose?
那你还管自己叫蝙蝠侠呢
You call yourself Batman.
是啊 我又没管自己叫
Yeah. I don't call myself
超级蝙蝠侠
Super Batman.
等等 他是蝙蝠侠吗
Wait, he's Batman?
不然我们干吗到这里来
What did you think we were doing here?
我还以为是来表哥家里吃饭呢
I thought this was the cousin's dinner.
他 布鲁斯韦恩是蝙蝠侠
He's... Bruce Wayne is Batman?
现在也不完全是
Not really. Not so much anymore.
知道吗
You know...
人们不需要我了
they don't really need me.
时过境迁
Things have changed.
哥谭现在是全球最安全的城市之一
Gotham's now one of the safest cities in the world.
可我需要你
Well, I... I need you.
我们需要你
We need you.
在我那边
In my timeline,
蝙蝠侠是我们的军师和领袖
Batman's our strategist, our leader.
这个世界需要超人
The world needs Superman.
而你是最好的侦探
You're the best detective in the world.
也许只有你才能帮我们找到他
You're probably the only person who can help me find him.
那么 你愿意帮我们吗
So, will you help us?
不愿意
Pass.
你是让我
把盐递过去吗
Like pass the salt?
布鲁斯
Bruce?
既然他不想帮忙
He doesn't want to help us...
我们就用他的蝙蝠设备自己查
we're gonna use his bat shit.
蝙蝠设备
Bat shit?
对 蝙蝠侠的各种高级设备
Yeah, his bat stuff, his bat things.
你先站上去
Stand on that thing.
好了 记得你共振穿地板那次吗
Okay, remember when you phased through the floor?
记得
Yeah.
好 现在你得再来一次
So, I need you to do that again.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
天啊
Dude!
这个地方真是爆炫
This place straight beeves!
爆炫
"Beeves"?
巴里
Barry!
我差点摔死在
I almost died
万丈深渊里
in an abyss!
美国有12805个叫克拉克肯特的人
12,805 Clark Kents in the US.
（搜索结果 克拉克肯特 12805条搜索结果）
这难道是我想的那样东西吗
Is this what I think it is?
我的天
Holy shit!
这是我小的时候
I used to see
在电视新闻上见过的玩意
this thing on the news when I was a kid!
好的
Okay, well...
缩小范围
refine search.
出生日期
Date of birth.
他不是在地球上出生的 是从外星来的
Wasn't born. He arrived.
巴里 快看
Oh, Barry, look!
我忙着呢
I'm busy.
忙什么啊
With what?
我在查过去这50年里
Looking for unidentified objects entering Earth's atmosphere
从堪萨斯附近领空 进入地球大气层的不明地外物体
anywhere near Kansas in the last 50 years.
他这里能进入国家航天局系统
He has a back door into NASA.
不愧是他
'Course he does.
不过 巴里
Yeah, but Barry,
你看看这个嘛
check this out.
这个小袋子会笑
This bag laughs.
行了 你能不能忙点正事
Okay, can't you take anything seriously?
别再瞎闹了
Stop messing around.
哥们 拜托
Dude, come on.
你在这里四处转过没有
Have you seen this place?
真的太酷了
It's amazing!
喂
Hello!
你现在还不知道事态有多严重吗
Has the gravity of this not sunk in for you?
别再瞎闹了 巴里
Stop messing around, Barry.
这是最后一次警告
I won't say it again.
真是
Yeesh.
抱歉 老妈
Sorry, Mom.
闭嘴
Shut up.
你根本不知道自己有多幸运
You have no idea how lucky you are.
根本不知道
No idea!
你觉得一切都是理所当然的
You take everything for granted.
根本不懂得感恩
You don't even appreciate...
一天到晚瞎晃
You just walk around thinking
以为自己可幽默 可时髦了
that you're so funny and so cool.
真丢人
And it's embarrassing,
因为其实
because
你哪条都不沾
you're not any of those things!
你少来好吗
Hey, screw you, man!
我干的全是你让我干的事
I've done nothing but everything you've asked.
你还害得我被闪电劈
You made me get struck by lightning!
我光着身子穿过了地板
I phased naked through the floor.
把约翰森夫人吓了个半死
And I terrified Mrs. Johannson.
没准我还得搬走
Now I'm probably gonna have to move.
你甚至都没告诉我你为什么会来这里
You won't even tell me why you're here.
那你能不能告诉我 为什么
But will you at least tell me why
无缘无故对我这么苛刻
you're being so mean to me... for no reason?
你把小猴子当成飞镖靶子
You used Monkey as a dartboard!
等等 什么
Wait, what?
算了
Forget it.
小猴子 等等
The monkey? Wait...
你跟我发这么大火 就因为
So, you're mad at me
我玩了一个玩具
for playing with a toy?
那不是普通玩具
It's not a toy.
是妈妈买给我们的
Mom bought us that monkey.
因为她就叫我们小猴子
'Cause she calls us Monkey.
还总是送我们和猴子有关的东西
She gives us monkey stuff all the time.
好吧
Right.
那个
Look...
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不太会和人相处
I'm not very good with people.
包括我自己
Even myself.
没事 哥们
Come on, dude.
你其实还好啦
You're... You're not that bad.
就是有的时候烦人了一点儿 但是
You can just be kind of a dick sometimes.
说实话 我这人是挺招人讨厌的
But let's face it. I am pretty obnoxious.
我特别容易激动
But I just get excited.
好啦 这地方真挺棒的 你说呢
Come on. This place is pretty cool, right?
是啊
Yeah.
那我
All right, well, um...
不打扰你了
I'll let you work.
我知道你在
I know you're there.
知道我在想什么吗
You know what I'm stuck on?
在想你用意面打的那个比方
That thing you said, with the spaghetti.
你当时说 有些时空之间的交汇
You said there were certain intersections
是避免不了的
that would always be inevitable.
（赠布鲁斯韦恩 你的朋友 阿尔弗雷德）
阿尔弗雷德当过你的助手
You had an Alfred.
在我那边 他也是蝙蝠侠的助手
My Bruce has an Alfred.
世界不一样 时间也不一样
Different worlds, different times...
但是你看
yet there it is.
有一些人
Certain people,
有一些事
certain events,
有些意大利面
certain strands of spaghetti,
会像磁铁一样相互吸引
drawn to each other like... like magnets.
我看了大量
I've read all about
时间悖论和因果循环的资料 但是
temporal paradoxes and causal loops. But
事实比理论复杂
this is more than that.
时间线之间那些不可避免的交汇点
Inevitable intersections
是任何理论都没法预测到的
are something none of the theories could have anticipated 'cause,
因为 还能怎么解释呢 只能说是
well, how do you explain that except for...
命运的安排
fate?
你还在听吗
If you are listening,
你父母的事我很遗憾
sorry about your parents.
我也只是想救我的父母
I'm just trying to save mine.
一定会有办法的
There has to be a way.
一定会有办法的 巴里
There is a way, Barry.
继续 继续
Just keep trying. Keep trying, Barry.
他找到超人了
Found him.
巴里 你快醒醒
Barry, wake up.
克拉克被雇佣兵组织
Clark's being held by a mercenary group
关在西伯利亚的秘密基地里
in a Siberian black site.
快起来 巴里
Get up, Barry.
山羊身上着火了
The goat's on fire.
我们得去趟俄罗斯
We're going to Russia.
真好
Sweet.
有咖啡
Mm. Coffee.
我们怎么去俄罗斯
How are we gonna get to Russia?
我会帮你们找到超人
I'll help you get this Superman.
然后 就要靠你们自己了
Then, you're on your own.
你
Oh!
你是
You're...
You are, you're...
没错
Yeah.
我是蝙蝠侠
I'm Batman.
计划是什么
So, what's the plan?
直接进去 拉上超人
We're just gonna, what, grab Superman
在敌人发现之前跑掉
and dip set before the block is hot?
不知道
I don't know.
你问问他
Hey, you should ask him.
你去问他
You ask him.
You should ask him.
好啊
Yeah,
我可不问
I'm not gonna ask him.
为什么 我还以为他是你好朋友
Why not? I thought Batman was supposed to be your friend.
又不是他 不是这个蝙蝠侠
Not this one. Not this Batman.
我们到了
We're here.
启动悬停模式
Activating hover mode.
打开弹射座椅
Ejector seat on.
弹射座椅
Ejector seat.
好吧 弹射还分步骤
Okay, there are stages.
你们身后都备了降落伞
You're strapped to your parachutes.
你的伞呢
Hey, where's yours?
这也太酷啦
This rips dicks!
一切正常 我们走
All clear. Let's move.
不要啊
Okay!
行 你们速度都快 就我慢
Good. Everybody's fast now but me.
怎么这么冷
Why is it so cold? - It's the Arctic, Barry.
这里是北极 巴里
他人呢
Where'd he go?
不知道 跟着脚印走就是了
I don't know. Just follow the footprints.
超人肯定就在下面
Superman would be down there for sure.
（俄语）有人闯进来了 快通知守卫
被发现了
Yeah. Okay.
（俄语）在这里
（俄语）开火
你干什么了
What did you do?
我移动了你 不过
I had to move you. But
没动多少
I just did it a little.
（俄语）找到了 在这儿
可能会很疼
This might hurt.
（俄语）集中火力
吐出来就好了
Just let it out.
（俄语）我的天啊
走吧
Let's go.
超人就被关在这里
That's where you keep Superman.
像一颗大铁蛋
Like a big scrotum.
（拒绝访问）
他要用这台翻盖手机黑进苏联的网络安全系统
He's gonna hack the Soviet security cyberscrotum with a flip phone?
（允许访问）
我把所有密码都试了一遍
I tried all the combinations.
成了
Yes!
该死
Shit.
卡尔-艾尔
Kal-El?
不是他
It's not him.
我们得走了
We've gotta go.
等等
Wait.
不能丢下她 她都这样了
We can't just leave her here. Look at her.
我来抱她 快走
I'll grab her. Just go!
有我在呢
I got you.
我来收拾这个蠢货
I'll handle this jabroni.
什么
What the...
巴里
Barry!
我中弹了
Somebody shot me!
我们得赶紧跑
Time to dip set!
（俄语）快把人放下
You, you lead the way!
不 别推我 别往下推
-Go! -Not that way! Not that way!
（俄语）把人放下 不然我就开枪了
天啊
Oh, God!
隐蔽
Cover!
要掉下来了 要下来了
It's coming around.
快啊 快啊
Hurry, hurry.
（俄语）集中火力射击线缆
不 别推我
No, no, no! This is bullshit!
该死
不
No!
起来
Come on.
快走
Let's go.
你根本没告诉我会中枪
You didn't tell me we could get shot!
你凭什么觉得我们不会中枪
Why would you assume we couldn't?
（俄语）跟上 跟上 跟上
好极了 我要死在苏联卫星脚下了
Oh, great! To die at the feet of a Sputnik.
大哥 我这膝盖还得用呢
Oh, man! I need this knee!
淡定 会自愈的
Stay calm. It'll heal.
快点儿
Come on.
不
（充能级别）
你体重多少公斤
How much do you weigh?
81公斤 他也是 加上她是199公斤
180. Each. Plus her, 440.
（11级）
（俄语）站住
（俄语）把人交出来 不然我就开枪了
抓稳了
Hold on.
（俄语）不许动
该死 他们追上来了 这边也来人了
Oh, great. They're here. They're over here, too.
斯米诺冰纯 对 斯米诺冰纯
Smirnoff Ice. Yes. Smirnoff Ice.
他们动真格了 巴里 闭嘴
Okay, they're serious. Barry, shut up.
好吧
Yeah, okay.
怎么办
What's the play?
蝙蝠侠 我们现在怎么办
Batman, what do we do? What now?
现在
Now...
我们得先保命
we try not to die.
（俄语）你要干什么
（俄语）射击
刚才那些要是有慢镜头就好了
Oh, you guys should've seen that in slo-mo.
我才意识到这么做有点儿欠考虑了
Yeah, I'm just realizing that I didn't really think this through.
虽然氪星有好人
There are good Kryptonians...
但那里同样也不缺十恶不赦的坏蛋
and then there are very, very bad Kryptonians.
（重要新闻 外星飞船出现在美国空军基地上空）
我当时信心十足地认为我们能在那里找到超人
And I was very confident that we were just gonna find Superman,
如果我们真的找到了超人
and if we found Superman,
那这一切就都迎刃而解了
then this would all be super simple.
你们是谁 我的天啊
- Who are you? - Holy Funyuns.
（危险罪犯）
你好
Hi.
我是巴里 我俩都是
-I... I'm Barry. -We're Barry.
我们本来要找卡尔-艾尔
We were trying to find Kal-El.
但最后我们只找到了你
But we found you instead.
你们找卡尔-艾尔干什么
What do you want with Kal-El?
我们想救他出来
We were trying to rescue him.
为什么
Why?
因为他是我朋友
Because he's my friend.
你认识他吗
Do you... Do you know him?
她好像火了 准备好
She looks mad. Get ready.
她会使用镭射眼 还会吹超级冷的冻气
She might do laser vision, or she might do, like, a freezy breath...
也可能直接乱扔东西
or she'll just start throwing crazy...
我的名字叫卡拉
My name is Kara.
佐-艾尔之女
Daughter of Zor-El.
卡尔-艾尔是我堂弟
Kal-El was my cousin.
等等 卡尔-艾尔是谁来着
Right, and who's Kal-El again?
就是超人
It's Superman.
不 你之前说他叫克拉克
No, 'cause you said that was Clark.
克拉克是谁
Who's Clark?
克拉克 是他在地球的名字
Clark is his human name.
克拉克
Clark.
我们离开家时他还是个婴儿
He was an infant when we left.
最后的氪星之子 而我
The last son of Krypton... I...
我奉命保护他
I was sent to protect him.
看样子在这个宇宙中他根本没有来到地球
It looks like he never made it to Earth in this universe.
我们两个的救生艇肯定是分开了
Our pods, they must have separated.
等等 你觉得一个小婴儿
Wait, so you thought a baby
可以帮我们对抗这个叫佐德的家伙
was gonna protect us from this Zod guy?
佐德将军到这儿来了
General Zod is here.
肯定是追踪救生艇的信号来的
He must have tracked my pod's signal.
我得走了
I have to go.
等会儿
Whoa, whoa, wait.
那个 你需要恢复一下体力
Well, you need to recover your strength.
这样 巴里
Actually, Barry...
你带她去屋顶
take her to the roof
让她在阳光下晒一会儿
and put her in the sun.
好
Yeah.
对 这完全没有问题
-Yeah. -Whatever, like if, I mean,
你可以用阳光充能
you're solar powered.
真了不起 我一直试着
Good for you. I've been trying to...
我帮你拿着
We'll take that with us.
我现在能
Um, am I cool to...
转过去了吗
turn around?
你现在穿的是
Are you dressed
红色披风
in a red cape?
你还能悬空
You're levitating?
这里一直这么吵吗
Is it always this loud?
这里很吵吗
Is it loud?
你感觉怎么样 体力有没有
Are you, uh, good? Do you feel, um...
恢复一点儿
strong yet, or...
很好 看起来就很强大
Yep, that seems, uh,
那什么
seems strong. You know...
刚才下边那个老巴里
old man Barry, down there,
他说如果我们不去阻止佐德队长
says if we don't stop Captain Zode,
他会害死成千上万的人
he'll kill thousands of people.
是数十亿人
Billions of people.
数十亿吗
Billions?
地球上的人
Of your people.
他们是好人
They're good people.
好人
Good people?
我们来到这个星球
We came to this planet
想找一个地方避难
looking for a safe place to live,
可他们却把我关进了牢笼
and they put me in a cage.
对 地球上确实有很多坏人
Yeah. A lot of humans are dicks.
但是 地球上
But then
还有小宝宝和芭蕾舞演员
there's babies and ballerinas.
还有娱乐摔跤手
And entertainment wrestlers.
有很多人值得被拯救
A lot of humans are worth saving.
那是你认为
Maybe to you.
我不是地球人
But I'm not a human.
我是氪星人
I'm a Kryptonian.
她走了
She's gone.
我必须重获超能力
I have to get my powers back.
要是能重演那次赋予我能力的意外
If I can re-create the accident that gave me my powers...
或许我可以重获神速力的青睐
maybe I can reconnect to the Speed Force...
那样我们就有机会对抗佐德了
and maybe we'd stand a chance against Zod.
或者 你会在这个过程中丧命
Or kill yourself in the process.
跟我说说吧
Tell me something.
如果你真的重获超能力
If you get your powers back,
你哪儿都能去
you can go anywhere.
比如另一条时间线 另一个宇宙
You can go to another timeline, another universe.
为什么要留下
Why do you wanna stay...
为守护这个世界而战
and fight to save this one?
因为我的妈妈活在这个世界里
Because this is the world where my mom lives.
我穿越时空就是为了救她
I went back in time to save her.
我绝不能再次失去她
I'm not gonna lose her again.
那孩子不知道吧
The kid doesn't know, does he?
这种事情要怎么跟他说
How do you tell someone something like that?
我失去了我的父母 但是
I lost my parents... but
那种痛苦
that pain...
造就了我
made me who I am.
没有那种经历 我也许会迷失自我
I'm not sure I know who I am without it, actually.
我大半辈子
I spent a lifetime...
都在试图纠正过去的错误
trying to right the wrongs of the past.
就好像
As if
披着个斗篷打击犯罪
putting on a cape and fighting crime
就能让我和父母重聚
would bring my parents back.
可你做到了
You actually did it.
看来
So...
你的计划就是
I guess the plan is
泼自己一身化学试剂的同时
to douse yourself in industrial chemicals
电击你自己
while electrocuting yourself?
没错
Yep.
要帮忙吗
Want some help?
太好了 我很需要你的帮助
Hell yeah.  That would be incredibly useful.
其实我已经拿了你一些药剂
I've actually already borrowed some chemicals
还有你的焊铁和耐热垫
and your soldering iron,
还坐在你的专座上
and I'm sitting in your bat-seat.
是不是有点儿不礼貌啊
Is that like a faux pas?
W号机 L号机 Z号机 请注意
Wilco, Lima, Zebra, be advised...
指挥部呼叫B-601号驾驶员
Air Command to Bravo 601.
主力编队 请确认管控范围
Primary teams, please confirm your AORs.
你竟然空手而来
You bring me nothing?
我警告过你们
I gave you a warning.
要是你们不能把那个氪星叛徒交给我们
Your failure to deliver the Kryptonian traitor
就会被视为对我们宣战
is being taken as an act of war.
开火 开火 开火
Fire, fire, fire!
武器准备就绪 开火
Weapons hot! Weapons hot! Open fire!
不要
No.
好了 等我拉动开关
Okay, when I throw the switch,
电流应该就会通过电线 把闪电直接引到风筝上面
the current should run up the wire and draw the lightning right to the kite.
给 把这个穿上
Here, put that on.
它不仅耐热 而且能防撞
It's heat and impact resistant.
一点儿保护措施
Should protect you a little.
关键就在于我不能有任何保护措施
Right, but the point is for me to not be protected.
好吧
Okay.
你得离远一点儿
You're gonna need to be out of the way.
好的
I will.
该上电刑了
Let's get electrocuted.
会成功的 对吧
This is going to work, right?
当然会成功的
Of course it's gonna work.
之前又不是没试过
Nothing we haven't done before.
这次还有蝙蝠侠帮忙
Besides, this time we have Batman.
没问题的
What could go wrong?
郑重声明 我觉得这很荒唐
Uh, for the record, I think this is insane.
离远点儿
Get back.
没事的 没事
It's fine. It's fine.
我们又见面了 闪电先生
Just you and me again, Mr. Lightning.
动手
Do it!
等等 什么 不好
Wait, what? No!
不行 等等 停下
No, wait! Stop!
停下
Stop!
天啊
Oh, God.
巴里 不要
Barry, no.
再来一次
Go again.
可是
But...
求你了
Please.
电路烧坏了
The circuit is fried.
我来帮你
I've got you.
喂
Hey.
巴里
Barry.
你跟上次一样没事 对吧
You're okay. It's like last time, right?
你快点儿自愈啊
So, you gotta heal now.
看 快看
Look, look, look!
可以了 成功了
It's working. It's working.
太好了 成功了
Yeah, it's working. Yeah.
太好了 他正在自愈
Yeah, he's healing. He's healing.
谢天谢地 他没事
Oh, my God. He's okay.
兄弟 你知不知道你差点儿把我吓死
Dude, you scared the shit out of me.
你醒了
You're awake.
感觉如何
How you feeling?
很慢
Slow.
也许这个能帮你
Maybe this will help.
完美
Yes!
太酷了 兄弟
Dude, come on!
真是太酷了
Irresistible!
天啊 重获力量太棒了
Man, feels good to be back.
当然
Yeah!
不过你穿的这是什么
And what are we wearing tonight?
喜欢吗
You like it?
我用蝙蝠侠的那套旧战服改的
I-I made it myself out of that old Batsuit.
改成了咱们战服的颜色和款式
But you know, I made it our colors and everything.
对了 你看这个
Well, check this out!
这身比较宽松
It's a bit more loose.
爆炫
It beeves.
兄弟
Dude...
你真这么觉得吗
you really mean that?
说实话
I mean, I don't...
其实我不知道“爆炫”是什么意思
I don't know what it means, exactly, to beeve.
不过听起来是个好词
But it seems like it's positive.
你怎么了
What are you doing?
你回来了
You came back.
很高兴你没事
I'm glad you're okay.
我有个问题想问你
I have to ask you something.
你在我被囚禁的地方找到我的时候
When you found me in that hole that they put me in...
发现我不是卡尔-艾尔
and I wasn't Kal-El...
为什么还要帮我
why did you help me?
因为你需要帮助
Because you needed help.
你知道这个符号代表什么吗
Do you know what this symbol stands for?
超级少女
Supergirl?
是希望 对吧
It means hope, right?
希望 对 是希望吗
Hope, yeah. Does it mean hope?
氪星是一个美丽的星球
Krypton was a beautiful place.
我们的特质是希望
We are a people of hope,
不是战争
not war.
这里是来自大都会的直播 就在几分钟之前
I'm coming to you live from Metropolis, where minutes ago, the mysterious flying...
佐德虽然是氪星人
Zod may be from Krypton,
但他绝对不能代表我们
but he is not my people.
那你的意思是
So, you're saying...
是的
Yes.
我会帮你们对抗佐德
I will help you fight Zod.
太好了
Yes!
这队伍有点儿意思
Interesting group.
你之前说
What did you say, uh...
我们叫什么来着
we were called again?
我们是正义联盟
We're the Justice League.
不对
No.
不对吗 不过
-No? -Well,
也算是吧
I mean, kinda.
我们还缺
We are short
一个真正的女神
one literal goddess...
一个笑面终结者
one friendly Terminator
一个超级人鱼
and super mermaid.
当然蝙蝠侠也是必不可少的
And we could definitely use a Batman.
你来吗
Are you in?
想大干一场
You wanna get nuts?
那就来吧
Let's get nuts.
在我来的世界 佐德一召唤超人就立刻现身了
In my world, Superman showed up right away when Zod called him out.
所以说我也不知道接下来会发生什么
So, as of now, we're in uncharted territory.
但是我知道
What I do know is
佐德以某种方式控制着创世引擎
that Zod somehow controls the World Engines,
它的破坏力非常惊人
which will be destroying much more
我们每晚一秒阻止他
than just Metropolis now
他就能摧毁一座规模相当于大都会的城市
with every passing second that we don't stop him.
巴里 你在干什么
Barry, what are you doing?
什么
What?
咱们的孩子们肯定想看
Our kids are gonna wanna see this.
你有孩子
Your kids?
我是说所有的孩子
Well, you know, like everybody's kids.
全世界所有的小孩儿
I mean, the children of the world.
他们肯定想看
They're gonna wanna see this.
我们马上就到了
We're getting close.
我负责空中作战 消灭他们的空中力量
I'm gonna stay airborne and take out their sky power.
巴里 这也就意味着
And Barry, just so we're clear
你和我两个人要对抗地面上的整个氪星人大军
what that essentially equates to is you and me versus the entire Kryptonian army.
好的
Chill.
我们要给卡拉争取时间 让她击败佐德
We need to buy Kara enough time to take out Zod.
别忘了你的战服不能像我的一样耗散能量
Oh, and remember that your suit doesn't dissipate energy like mine
所以你不能一直跑 否则会积累过多的电荷
so you need to take breaks, otherwise you're gonna build up too much charge.
等等 什么
Wait, what?
抓稳
Hold on!
稳住
Hold on.
这就是我们要保护的人吗
The humans we came to protect?
他们不知道我们是友军
They don't know we're on their side.
佐德
Zod.
卡拉佐-艾尔
Kara Zor-El.
终于把你等来了
We've been waiting for you.
把他拖走 你上 我来掩护
-Drag him out, drag him! -You go! I'll cover!
等一下 那个来自太空的巨怪
Okay, and the space giant...
还有那个女杀人狂 也要我们对付吗
and Mistress Murder... are our responsibility, too?
别去想他们 冷静下来
Don't think about them, okay? Calm down.
我们先解决那边的敌人
We're just gonna start with those guys over there.
没错 他们都是氪星人 我们干不掉
And yeah, they're Kryptonian, and we won't be able to kill them,
但我们可以帮卡拉拖住他们
but we can slow them down for her.
一个一个来
One at a time.
好吗
Okay?
我先去打掉他们的武器 然后你再上
I'm gonna disarm them, and then you'll engage.
揍他们
Punch 'em.
走吧 芭比
Come on, Barbie.
去派对狂欢
Let's go party?
糟糕
Okay, ow!
好了 没事了
Okay. It's okay.
你没事 快起来
You're okay. Come on.
天啊 他们太快了
Jesus, they're fast.
没错 但是不如我们快
Yes, but not as fast as us.
地球的改造已经开始
Terraforming has begun.
只有这个世界灭亡
This world must die
我们那个世界才能重生
so that ours may live again.
不好 我们快走 快走
Oh, my God. We gotta go. We gotta go.
丹尼 走
Dan, Danny, go,
走
go!
氪星已经灭亡了 佐德
Krypton is gone, Zod.
你的叔叔
Your uncle...
乔-艾尔
Jor-El...
把氪星
hid the key
能够重生的关键
to Krypton's rebirth
藏在了一个氪星孩子身上
inside a Kryptonian child.
他把重启氪星生命所必需的基因资料
All the genetic material needed to start again
编码进了他的DNA
coded inside the DNA,
然后用逃生舱 把他送来了地球
then sent to Earth in an escape pod.
他不在这里 你已经失败了
He's not here. You have failed.
我们找到他了
We found him.
我们拦截了他的逃生舱
We intercepted his pod.
但你那个堂弟并不是我们要找的人
But your cousin was not the one we needed.
你才是那个人
You are the one.
卡拉佐-艾尔
Kara Zor-El.
我们需要的
It is your blood...
是你的血液
we must harvest.
你们把卡尔-艾尔怎么了
What did you do to Kal-El?
你的牺牲将会让我们的氪星
Your sacrifice that will allow
重获新生
Krypton to live again.
你们到底做了什么
What did you do?
那个孩子
The infant did
并没有活下来
not survive.
听着 新计划
Look, new plan.
我来制造一阵龙卷风
I'm gonna create a cyclonic diversion.
然后你发动进攻 用全力
And you're gonna just come in, hard.
这次直接用脚踹
Feet first this time.
漂亮
Yes!
巴里 你看到了吗
Barry, did you see that?
小心 你积累的电荷太多了
Be careful. You're accumulating too much charge.
要是我发射电流攻击这家伙呢
What if I just Emperor this guy?
不行 快住手
No, no, no!
巴里 刚才那招并没有我想的那么蠢
Barry, that was actually only half stupid!
但是 如果你想活着继续用那招
But if you're gonna do that and not die,
你需要想办法组成电回路
you need to complete the circuit somehow.
试着把手放在一起 像这样
Try putting your hands together, like this.
糟了
Oh, shit.
你可以的
You're ready.
冲啊
Let's go!
歌词大意 来吧
我好像遇到了一点儿麻烦
? I seem to think I think I got a little situation ?
所以听我说
? So listen to me,
或许你能帮上忙
sister Listen maybe you can help ?
我对许多问题都有自己的思考
? I think I gave a lot of Problems my consideration ?
但我似乎总在为别人考虑
? But not for me It always seem to be For someone else ?
为什么其他人好像总在休假
? Why all the people always Seem to just be on vacation ?
我得到什么好处了吗 什么都没有
? What do I get from it I don't get anything at all ?
我就像一个装着各种负能量的垃圾桶
? I'm like a trash can Holding all the information ?
这种感觉让我无地自容
? And every single time It leaves me Feeling two feet tall ?
只有一种答案 只有一种答案
? And only one I'm taking ?
我去对付那个大家伙
I'm going after the big one.
我被击中了
I've been hit.
布鲁斯 能听到吗
Bruce, do you copy?
卡拉呢
Where's Kara?
你快去找她
You go find her.
布鲁斯
Bruce!
弹射模式 故障
Ejection mode failure. Ejection mode failure.
安息吧 卡拉佐-艾尔
Rest, Kara Zor-El.
我要坠毁了
Going down.
但我还要拉个垫背的
But I'm not going alone.
不 不要
No, no, no,
布鲁斯
Bruce!
布鲁斯 快弹射
Bruce, eject!
布鲁斯 赶紧弹
Bruce, just eject...
不
No!
卡拉
Kara.
这种事不应该
Isn't supposed...
不应该发生的
Not supposed to happen...
卡拉死了
Kara's dead.
他们都死了
They're both dead.
但还有办法 对吧
But they don't have to be, right?
因为我们可以穿越
'Cause we can go back.
就像你之前那样
Like you did.
你的速度还不够快
You're not fast enough yet.
是吗
You sure?
巴里
Barry!
巴里 等等
Barry, wait!
到这儿够了吗
Is this back enough?
我觉得够了
Yeah, I guess so.
听着 巴里 我
Listen, Barry, I...
怎么了
What?
没事的 我们肯定能搞定
It's okay. We can fix this.
你知道怎么做吗 我已经想好做什么了
You know what you're gonna change? I know what I'm gonna change.
我去对付那个大家伙
I'm going after the big one.
布鲁斯 先别打 那艘战舰外面有护盾
Bruce, pull off. That gunship is shield-protected.
收到
Roger that.
他肯定没有
Bet he's not.
谁
Who?
那个太空巨怪
Space giant?
没错 赶紧把他干掉
Yes, yes, please take him out.
太好了
Yes.
好了
我来了
别
No.
你会好的
It'll be okay.
这次不行了
Not this time, kid.
别的时间线也许行
Maybe some other time.
我们救不了你 是吗
We can't bring you back, can we?
你已经救过了
You already did.
已经救过了
来吧 巴里
Come on, Barry.
快起来啊 快啊
Gotta get up. Come on.
巴里
Barry.
再来一次
We go again.
巴里
Barry.
我们走吧
Let's just go.
巴里 好了 我们快走
Barry, come on. Let's just go.
巴里 这样做毫无意义
Barry, there's no point.
巴里
Barry!
共振
Phase!
来 我帮你拔出来
Okay, I have to pull it out.
不用 我没事 我得把它拔出来
-I have to pull it out. -No, I'm okay.
我没事 我应该早点儿停下的 巴里 用共振
You have to phase again. Barry, phase again. I'm okay. I just should've stopped sooner.
再来
Again.
巴里
Barry.
等等 我们能不能先停一下
Okay, can we please just take a minute?
抱歉 伙计
Sorry, dude.
兄弟 当然可以了
Yeah, bro, of course.
这是我们的能力
That's the whole thing.
想停多久 我们就能停多久
We can take as much time as it takes.
不 不是
No,
我不是那个意思 我
that's not what I mean. Hey!
怎么样 好点儿了吗
Okay, you good?
走吧 我需要你帮忙
Come on. I need you in there.
快来吧
Let's go.
巴里 拜托 先听我说
Barry, please, just listen to me!
你去哪儿了
Where were you?
你一直都站在这里没动吗
What, you just stand here the whole time?
巴里
Barry,
这是一个无法避免的交汇点
this is an inevitable intersection.
快点儿停手吧 巴里
You have to stop. Barry!
不 巴里 等等
No, Barry, wait!
听着 巴里
Barry, listen.
我有话要对你说
There's something I should tell you.
我一开始尝试回到过去
I went back in time initially
是因为
because...
是因为妈妈死了
Yeah, because Mom died.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
这不重要
It doesn't matter.
不是吗
Does it?
我必须纠正我犯下的错
You know that I have to undo what I did.
不
No.
你没有做错
It's not a mistake.
我们能救她
We can save her.
也可以救他们
And we can save them.
我们救不了
No, we can't.
这就是布鲁斯之前所说的
This is what Bruce was talking about.
巴里 这无法避免
Barry, this is inevitable.
我们就算尝试一百万次
We can try a million times,
也没办法改变这一切
and we're not gonna be able to fix this.
无论我们做什么
No matter what we do...
世界都会灭亡
this world dies.
就在今天
Today.
你自己看看
Look around.
我们把这里搞得一团糟
Look at the damage we're causing.
现在必须停手了 好吗
Now we have to stop. Okay?
听着 我本来只是回家洗衣服
Look, I was just doing my laundry.
是你突然出现
You're the one who came
跟我说我是一个超级英雄
and told me that I'm a superhero.
现在 你又是什么意思
And now you're saying what?
你又不想让我当了
You don't want me to be?
不好意思 现在太晚了
Well, guess what! It's too late!
我就是
I am...
闪电侠
...the Flash.
我可以拯救所有人
And I can save everyone.
谁都不会死
Nobody dies!
巴里
Barry...
有些问题注定无解
not every problem has a solution.
Not every problem has a solution.
有时我们只能放弃
Sometimes we just have to let go.
有时候你只能放弃
Sometimes you just have to let go.
放弃
Let go
救妈妈
of Mom?
这么多条时间线 总有一条妈妈会活着
She'll always be alive, somewhere in time.
一定会
Always.
但不是这一条
Just not for us.
简直胡说八道
You're full of shit, dude.
我要回去了
I'm going back.
你要回去让妈妈死吗
You're going back to kill Mom?
不行
No!
你不能走
You're staying!
别走 待在这儿
You stay, right here.
就让我再试一次
Just give me one more time.
巴里 站住
Barry, stop!
你站住
You, stop!
初次见面不太愉快
Feel like we got off on the wrong foot.
重新认识一下
Let's start again.
我是闪电侠
I'm the Flash.
你叫什么
What's your name?
我的经历
I've lived...
超乎你的想象
more than you can dream.
答非所问
Not an answer.
你是在背台词吗
Do you, like, rehearse that?
快离开这儿 巴里
Get out of here, Barry!
那个伤疤 你
That scar, you...
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
你是
So, you're...
You are...
没错 我就是
Yes, I am...
你
you.
马上就成功了
We are so close.
我就要弄清楚了
I've got it almost figured out.
你这样做有多长时间了
How long have you been doing this?
多长时间并不重要
Time is inconsequential.
来吧 巴里
Come on, Barry.
快看天上 有只鸟
Up in the sky! It's a bird!
那是飞机
It's a plane!
是超人
It's Superman!
绝对万无一失
Purrfectly foolproof.
只有小丑会这么想
Only the Joker would think of that.
看看正在发生的这一切
Please just look at what's happening.
这些世界
These worlds...
正在相互冲撞和崩毁
...they're colliding and collapsing.
这都怪我们
We did this.
我们正在破坏万物的结构
W-We're destroying the fabric of everything.
你必须马上停手
You have to stop.
等我成功了 这些就都会停了
It stops once I've fixed it!
这也不全是你的错 巴里
It's not entirely your fault, Barry.
9月29日那天 是我把你推出了时空之碗
I pushed you out of the Chronobowl on that September 29
让你帮我踏上了这条路
so you could start me on this path.
你觉得我们这个悖论怎么样
How do you like our endless paradox?
是我本人让你创造了我
I made you create me...
而现在你却成了
and now you're the one...
我的阻碍
in my way.
无论我多么接近打赢这场战斗
No matter how close I get to winning this fight...
你都会回去
you go back
导致妈妈死去
and let Mom die.
你才是不可避免的交汇点
You're the inevitable intersection.
你确实需要放手
And you do have to let go.
他是什么意思
What's he talking about?
你是我的英雄
You're my hero.
你这是干什么
What did you do?
别害怕 会愈合的
Hey, hey. Don't worry. It's gonna heal.
会愈合的
It's gonna heal.
我刚才是想
I just wanted to...
巴里
告诉妈妈我爱她
You tell Mom I love her.
别忘了这罐西红柿
Don't forget the tomatoes.
我小时候特别爱吃这种麦片
I used to love that cereal when I was a kid.
是吧
Yeah.
我儿子也特别喜欢吃
My son goes nuts for it.
可惜要停产了
They stop making it.
我听到消息说
Well, I know they were talking
这种麦片就要停产了
about discontinuing it.
我们认识吗
Do I know you?
不 我平时不住这附近
No, I'm not from around here.
我是来看妈妈的
I was just visiting my mom.
没准我认识她
Maybe I know her.
她叫什么名字
What's her name?
她是天底下最好
She's the best...
也是最善良的人
and kindest person in the world.
你还好吗
You okay?
嗯 我就是
Yeah, I'm just...
我会想她的
I'm really gonna miss her.
我知道 我只是超市里的一个陌生阿姨
I know I'm just... a random lady in a store.
要我抱抱你吗
But do you want a hug?
好
Sure.
对不起
I'm sorry.
不要这么说
Oh, don't say that.
你特意来看妈妈 她一定特别感动
Your mom must be grateful you came to visit her.
有你是她的福气
She's very lucky to have you.
有她是我的福气
I'm very lucky to have her.
那你可得亲口告诉她
You have to tell her that.
当妈妈的就喜欢听这样的话
Moms like to hear these kind of things.
相信我吧
Believe me.
歌词大意 世界离我越来越远
虽然我的身体已经不在了
世界离我越来越远
我把灵魂留在了这里
来这里找她
我爱你 妈妈
Love you, Mom.
我爱你更多
I love you more.
我爱你更早
I loved you first.
再见
Bye.
（西红柿罐头）
我回来了
I'm back.
（不确定你什么时候回来 庭审现场见 艾瑞斯）
该死
Shit!
庭审
Court!
在此前的庭审中 被认定为
...original trial was initially...
非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.
（法官）
正如我刚才所说
As I was saying...
这条编号为F的录像证据在此前的庭审中
the same security camera footage, Exhibit F in the original trial,
（证据F）
被认定为无效证据
was initially considered useless,
但是这一次
but has now
我们借助韦恩企业的最新技术
been enhanced, using the latest tech
提高了画面质量
from Wayne Enterprises.
录像内容印证了
It confirms the alibi
艾伦先生的不在场证明
Mr. Allen has argued,
也和他儿子 巴里
and his son, Barry,
当年的口供完全一致
has corroborated, since day one.
（证据F 修复后）
请看
Here.
大家可以清楚地看到 被告人艾伦先生
Right here, you can clearly see my client, Mr. Allen,
正从货架最上层拿取西红柿罐头
reaching for a can of tomatoes on the top shelf.
艾伦先生 您可以 再跟我们讲讲之前发生的事吗
Mr. Allen, Mr. Allen, can you tell us a bit more about what happened, please?
关于这个
Well, um...
西红柿从货架最底层移到了最上层
the tomatoes moved from the bottom shelf to the top shelf,
也就导致了
and subsequently,
煮熟的意面又变生了
uncooked the spaghetti.
说完了
Unquote.
抱歉 您刚刚说的是什么啊
I'm sorry, that makes absolutely no sense.
这是什么意思 先生
What are you talking about, sir?
谢谢大家
Thank you.
非常感谢各位
Thank you so much.
采访结束了 谢谢
We're good here. Thank you.
我刚才讲得还行吗
Did I give a good quote?
当然 尤其是意面那句
Yeah. Spaghetti.
既然说到了吃的 我在想
Hey, speaking of food, I was thinking, um...
你应该约我吃饭
you should ask me to dinner.
和我吃晚饭
D-Dinner with me?
没错 约会 巴里
Yes, a date, Barry.
艾瑞斯 可以共进晚餐吗
Iris West, do you wanna dinner-date me?
我很乐意
I'd love to.
谢谢
Thank you.
我也很乐意
I'd love to also.
打给我
Call me.
歌词大意 生活真的会给人惊喜
天啊 生活真会给人惊喜
（布鲁斯韦恩）
布鲁斯
Bruce!
恭喜啊
Congratulations.
谢谢
Thank you.
你可不知道我听见你的声音有多高兴
You have no idea how good it is to hear your voice.
等下次见了面 我有好多事要跟你讲
I... I have so much to tell you the next time I see you, Bruce.
你说得对 是我没把你的话当真
You were right. Okay? And I didn't listen.
结果事情发展得非常 非常离谱
And things did get very, very weird,
但是我把一切都恢复了 我向你保证
but I put everything back, I promise.
我的车马上就到
I'm pulling up now.
太好了
Oh, great.
先生 先生
Sir, sir!
先生 请您看镜头
- Back up, please. - Shot!
这和您受到的指控有关联吗
Was it backed by your own allegation?
见鬼了 这又是谁
Who the fuck is this?
抱歉 韦恩先生今天不接受采访
He's not answering any questions.
请大家退后
巴里
Hey, Barry.
不 那个谁呢
No, wh-where's...
你是 你
You're, you...
不 你不是
No. You can't...
你
You...
你不是蝙蝠侠啊
You're not Batman.
你失忆了吗
What's wrong with you?
（本故事基于DC漫画角色创作）
? When the morning comes ?
? You can't keep lettin' it Get you down ?
剧名：闪电侠
都说了我新陈代谢很快的
I've told you it's my metabolism, right?
我是怎么都喝不醉的
I can't get drunk.
我也是喝不“坠”的
I can't get drink either.
听着
Listen.
听着 我尽量
Listen, I'm,
好了 别喝了
'cause I'm trying to... No, no, no.
我尽量用最简单的方式解释一下这是怎么回事
'Cause what I'm trying to explain as simply as I possibly can, I promise...
他们都是蝙蝠侠
They were all Batman.
他们都是布鲁斯韦恩
They were all Bruce Wayne.
但是他们各自又是完全不同的人
But each of them was a completely different person.
在另外一条线时间
So, on the other line-time...
时间线
Timeline.
我还是同一个人
...I'm the same guy?
对 基本上差不太多
Yeah. Actually, pretty much.
你招人喜欢 多毛
You're lovable, furry...
讲义气 超级爱吃培根
loyal, motivated by bacon.
好吧 听着
All right, listen.
感谢你把情况简化以后再讲给我听
Thank you for making it more simpler for me,
简化先生
Mr. Simple More.
我已经尽力了
Yeah, I'm doing my best.
听着 你没听明白我要说的重点
Look, you're missing the larger premise here.
在我的时间线
In my timeline,
当我
when I...
好了 来吧
All right, come on.
快起来 海王兄弟
Up, up, Broseidon.
行了 快起来
All right, come on.
你不是要睡沙发吗
I thought you were gonna sleep on the couch.
亚瑟 我家就在这儿
Arthur, I live right here.
哈里
Harry?
我家在这儿 没事的
I live right here. It's okay.
好吧
Okay.
对了
Oh, hey.
再来几瓶啤酒
More beer.
快去快回
Go fast.
等等
Oh, here!
这个
Here.
拿这个换酒
Pay with this.
亚瑟 这可是亚特兰蒂斯的珍宝
Arthur, this is Atlantean treasure.
就这么跟他们说
You... You tell them that.
没有钱买一身水手服
? Got no money For the sailor suit I... ?
对 我是个水手
-Yep. -? I'm a sailor... ?
你是水手
You're a sailor.
他没事
He's fine.